<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="transform.xsl"?>
<news_list>
    <article>
        <title>Southern Mississippi fraternity rush prank goes awry, flamingo dies</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/us/mississippi-fraternity-prank-flamingo-death/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141010192035-flamingo-deaths-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413053580000</timestamp>
        <author>Michael Martinez,</author>
        <author>Carma Hassan</author>
        <author>Amanda Watts,</author>
        <corpus>However, the fraternity stunt at 1 a.m. Tuesday went awry when one student decided he wanted a Chilean pink flamingo instead -- to take back to the fraternity house, according to police and officials. The student climbed a 10-foot fence and threw a T-shirt over the bird, zoo officials said. What started as an innocent stunt has now resulted in the flamingo's death, a student charged with a felony, nine other suspects being investigated for conspiracy, and the indefinite suspension of the school's 65-year-old Delta Mu chapter of the Pi Kappa Alpha fraternity, officials said. A second flamingo later died from injuries caused by the pranksters' "attack," zoo officials said. The second flamingo was a male and the mate of the first flamingo, and the male "sustained his injuries by defending his mate," the zoo said on its Facebook page. Devin Nottis, 19, was arrested and charged with grand larceny, Hattiesburg Police said. He and his attorney couldn't be immediately reached for comment on Friday. The case against the nine other suspects will be sent to the Forrest County District Attorney's Office for a "grand jury to pursue an indictment," police said. $2,000 birds The accusation led to a felony charge because a Chilean flamingo is worth $2,000, above the felony threshold of $500, said Richard Taylor, the executive director of the Hattiesburg Convention Commission, which operates the Hattiesburg Zoo. The fraternity members realized "that this was a really, really bad decision" when they saw the flamingo in their house and "instructed that the bird be taken away," Taylor said. But the student accused of stealing the bird decided to leave the bird on a nearby bicycling trail, Taylor said. During that transport, one of the flamingo's legs was broken, and when the bird was found the next morning, it was unable to move and had to be euthanized, Taylor said. 'Terrible and heinous' Nottis has been placed on interim suspension from the university. None of the others being investigated had been suspended as of Friday, said Southern Mississippi Vice President for Student Affairs Dr. Joe Paul. "The university is taking swift and appropriate action in response to this incident," Paul said. "This is a terrible and heinous act that has occurred, and inconsistent with the values of our institution." The Pi Kappa Alpha International Fraternity said it was "disgusted and outraged" by the incident. "The alleged actions by these students are inexcusable and indefensible. It is without hesitation that the chapter has been suspended. The individuals involved will also be brought up for expulsion" from the fraternity, said the fraternity's executive vice president, Justin A. Buck. Police said they received a call at 2 a.m. Tuesday about several people possibly inside the zoo. The caller also said several young men were throwing eggs at a truck, police said. The caller said the males "had a duck or a goose with them," the police report said. Responding officers, however, didn't find anyone. Zoo video breaks case By 8:30 a.m., officers responded to a call about "a pink flamingo on the side of the road," the police report said. Video footage from the zoo showed "four subjects" walking through the zoo about 1:15 a.m., police said. The zoo posted the video clip to its Facebook page and asked for the public's help in identifying the four people, Taylor said. A tipster told the zoo that "there was a couple of Twitter feeds that seemed to point towards some knowledge of this, if not participation," Taylor said. The information was turned over to police. Death of the male mate In the aftermath of the prank, zoo officials discovered a male flamingo was showing unusual behavior. He stood by himself, not with the flock. He also had abrasions, Taylor said. The male then died. "We took it in for a necropsy, which revealed it had severe internal damage consistent with blunt force trauma," Taylor said. Some of the male's internal organs ruptured, Taylor said. "It was trying to protect the mate and it was probably kicked or hit away in some fashion," Taylor said. As police continue their investigation, the zoo is evaluating whether to hire a night security officer, Taylor said.</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Southern Mississippi fraternity rush prank goes awry, flamingo dies</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/us/mississippi-fraternity-prank-flamingo-death/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141010192035-flamingo-deaths-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413053580000</timestamp>
        <author>Michael Martinez,</author>
        <author>Carma Hassan</author>
        <author>Amanda Watts,</author>
        <corpus>However, the fraternity stunt at 1 a.m. Tuesday went awry when one student decided he wanted a Chilean pink flamingo instead -- to take back to the fraternity house, according to police and officials. The student climbed a 10-foot fence and threw a T-shirt over the bird, zoo officials said. What started as an innocent stunt has now resulted in the flamingo's death, a student charged with a felony, nine other suspects being investigated for conspiracy, and the indefinite suspension of the school's 65-year-old Delta Mu chapter of the Pi Kappa Alpha fraternity, officials said. A second flamingo later died from injuries caused by the pranksters' "attack," zoo officials said. The second flamingo was a male and the mate of the first flamingo, and the male "sustained his injuries by defending his mate," the zoo said on its Facebook page. Devin Nottis, 19, was arrested and charged with grand larceny, Hattiesburg Police said. He and his attorney couldn't be immediately reached for comment on Friday. The case against the nine other suspects will be sent to the Forrest County District Attorney's Office for a "grand jury to pursue an indictment," police said. $2,000 birds The accusation led to a felony charge because a Chilean flamingo is worth $2,000, above the felony threshold of $500, said Richard Taylor, the executive director of the Hattiesburg Convention Commission, which operates the Hattiesburg Zoo. The fraternity members realized "that this was a really, really bad decision" when they saw the flamingo in their house and "instructed that the bird be taken away," Taylor said. But the student accused of stealing the bird decided to leave the bird on a nearby bicycling trail, Taylor said. During that transport, one of the flamingo's legs was broken, and when the bird was found the next morning, it was unable to move and had to be euthanized, Taylor said. 'Terrible and heinous' Nottis has been placed on interim suspension from the university. None of the others being investigated had been suspended as of Friday, said Southern Mississippi Vice President for Student Affairs Dr. Joe Paul. "The university is taking swift and appropriate action in response to this incident," Paul said. "This is a terrible and heinous act that has occurred, and inconsistent with the values of our institution." The Pi Kappa Alpha International Fraternity said it was "disgusted and outraged" by the incident. "The alleged actions by these students are inexcusable and indefensible. It is without hesitation that the chapter has been suspended. The individuals involved will also be brought up for expulsion" from the fraternity, said the fraternity's executive vice president, Justin A. Buck. Police said they received a call at 2 a.m. Tuesday about several people possibly inside the zoo. The caller also said several young men were throwing eggs at a truck, police said. The caller said the males "had a duck or a goose with them," the police report said. Responding officers, however, didn't find anyone. Zoo video breaks case By 8:30 a.m., officers responded to a call about "a pink flamingo on the side of the road," the police report said. Video footage from the zoo showed "four subjects" walking through the zoo about 1:15 a.m., police said. The zoo posted the video clip to its Facebook page and asked for the public's help in identifying the four people, Taylor said. A tipster told the zoo that "there was a couple of Twitter feeds that seemed to point towards some knowledge of this, if not participation," Taylor said. The information was turned over to police. Death of the male mate In the aftermath of the prank, zoo officials discovered a male flamingo was showing unusual behavior. He stood by himself, not with the flock. He also had abrasions, Taylor said. The male then died. "We took it in for a necropsy, which revealed it had severe internal damage consistent with blunt force trauma," Taylor said. Some of the male's internal organs ruptured, Taylor said. "It was trying to protect the mate and it was probably kicked or hit away in some fashion," Taylor said. As police continue their investigation, the zoo is evaluating whether to hire a night security officer, Taylor said.</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Instead of Columbus Day, some U.S. cities celebrate Indigenous People's Day</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/living/columbus-day-indigenous-people-day/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141010193716-indigenous-peoples-day-restricted-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413203220000</timestamp>
        <author>Emanuella Grinberg</author>
        <corpus>For the first time this year, Seattle and Minneapolis will recognize the second Monday in October as "Indigenous People's Day." The cities join a growing list of jurisdictions choosing to shift the holiday's focus from Christopher Columbus to the people he encountered in the New World and their modern-day descendants. The Seattle City Council voted last week to reinvent the holiday to celebrate "the thriving cultures and values of Indigenous Peoples in our region." The Minneapolis City Council approved a similar measure in April "to reflect upon the ongoing struggles of Indigenous people on this land, and to celebrate the thriving culture and value that Dakota, Ojibwa and other indigenous nations add to our city." The Seattle School Board followed suit along with Portland Public Schools, where officials say Indigenous People's Day will not replace Columbus Day but supplement it. Schools across the country have been working for years to clarify Columbus' role in history. "It's not about one or the other, it's about how do we get a complete picture to understand where we're at in history, and how we got there?" said Portland School Board member Greg Belisle, according to the Oregonian. In many cities, Columbus Day is a celebration of Italian-American heritage, leading to opposition to the recasting of Columbus Day. "Italian-Americans are deeply offended," Lisa Marchese, a lawyer affiliated with the Order Sons of Italy in America, told The Seattle Times."By this resolution, you say to all Italian-Americans that the city of Seattle no longer deems your heritage or your community worthy of recognition." President Benjamin Harrison established a celebration of Columbus Day in 1892, the 400th anniversary of Columbus' landing in the Bahamas in 1492. The holiday started being celebrated on the second Monday in October in 1971. Today, 16 states, including Alaska, Hawaii and Oregon, don't recognize Columbus Day as a public holiday. South Dakota has celebrated Native American Day since 1990. Opinion: What to tell your kid about Christopher Columbus Berkeley, California, is thought to be the first city to adopt Indigenous People's Day in 1992, building on international efforts to end the celebration of Columbus' "discovery" of the New World. The International Day of the World's Indigenous People is celebrated on August 9 thanks to a 1994 United Nations General Assembly resolution. The Italian explorer and his namesake holiday have long been controversial. Despite what American schoolchildren may have learned about when "Columbus sailed the ocean blue," supporters of Indigenous People's Day believe Columbus should not be celebrated for "discovering" America. Indigenous people had been living in the "New World" for centuries by the time he arrived, and his voyages established lasting connections between Europe and Americans that paved the way for its colonization, leading to the subjugation and decimation of the indigenous population. "Learning about the history of Columbus and transforming this day into a celebration of indigenous people and a celebration of social justice ... allows us to make a connection between this painful history and the ongoing marginalization, discrimination and poverty that indigenous communities face to this day," Seattle Councilmember Kshama Sawant said.</corpus>
        <section></section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Instead of Columbus Day, some U.S. cities celebrate Indigenous People's Day</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/living/columbus-day-indigenous-people-day/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141010193716-indigenous-peoples-day-restricted-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413203220000</timestamp>
        <author>Emanuella Grinberg</author>
        <corpus>For the first time this year, Seattle and Minneapolis will recognize the second Monday in October as "Indigenous People's Day." The cities join a growing list of jurisdictions choosing to shift the holiday's focus from Christopher Columbus to the people he encountered in the New World and their modern-day descendants. The Seattle City Council voted last week to reinvent the holiday to celebrate "the thriving cultures and values of Indigenous Peoples in our region." The Minneapolis City Council approved a similar measure in April "to reflect upon the ongoing struggles of Indigenous people on this land, and to celebrate the thriving culture and value that Dakota, Ojibwa and other indigenous nations add to our city." The Seattle School Board followed suit along with Portland Public Schools, where officials say Indigenous People's Day will not replace Columbus Day but supplement it. Schools across the country have been working for years to clarify Columbus' role in history. "It's not about one or the other, it's about how do we get a complete picture to understand where we're at in history, and how we got there?" said Portland School Board member Greg Belisle, according to the Oregonian. In many cities, Columbus Day is a celebration of Italian-American heritage, leading to opposition to the recasting of Columbus Day. "Italian-Americans are deeply offended," Lisa Marchese, a lawyer affiliated with the Order Sons of Italy in America, told The Seattle Times."By this resolution, you say to all Italian-Americans that the city of Seattle no longer deems your heritage or your community worthy of recognition." President Benjamin Harrison established a celebration of Columbus Day in 1892, the 400th anniversary of Columbus' landing in the Bahamas in 1492. The holiday started being celebrated on the second Monday in October in 1971. Today, 16 states, including Alaska, Hawaii and Oregon, don't recognize Columbus Day as a public holiday. South Dakota has celebrated Native American Day since 1990. Opinion: What to tell your kid about Christopher Columbus Berkeley, California, is thought to be the first city to adopt Indigenous People's Day in 1992, building on international efforts to end the celebration of Columbus' "discovery" of the New World. The International Day of the World's Indigenous People is celebrated on August 9 thanks to a 1994 United Nations General Assembly resolution. The Italian explorer and his namesake holiday have long been controversial. Despite what American schoolchildren may have learned about when "Columbus sailed the ocean blue," supporters of Indigenous People's Day believe Columbus should not be celebrated for "discovering" America. Indigenous people had been living in the "New World" for centuries by the time he arrived, and his voyages established lasting connections between Europe and Americans that paved the way for its colonization, leading to the subjugation and decimation of the indigenous population. "Learning about the history of Columbus and transforming this day into a celebration of indigenous people and a celebration of social justice ... allows us to make a connection between this painful history and the ongoing marginalization, discrimination and poverty that indigenous communities face to this day," Seattle Councilmember Kshama Sawant said.</corpus>
        <section></section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Teal pumpkins try to change Halloween for kids with food allergies</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/health/halloween-safety-food-allergies/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141009104840-teal-pumpkin-project-halloween-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413202260000</timestamp>
        <author>Sara Cheshire</author>
        <corpus>Chocolate is frightening if you're allergic to milk, and a candy bar with nuts can be deadly. With eggs, soy and wheat also common allergies in kids, according to the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, finding treats without tricks can be a challenge on Halloween night. That's why the Food Allergy Research &amp; Education organization wants Halloween lovers to go teal this holiday. Their Teal Pumpkin Project encourages people to place a teal-painted pumpkin outside their door if they're offering non-foods treats, such as small toys, stickers and crayons. A flyer can also be printed from the website. The idea is taking off online. Food Allergy Research &amp; Education's first Facebook post about the Teal Pumpkin Project, reached 2.7 million people in less than 72 hours, the organization reported. Posts about the project have been shared a combined 31,000 times. This year marks the first time the idea has been promoted nationally. "The Teal Pumpkin Project is an easy way to make a big impact in your community. Food allergies can be life-threatening, and they affect 1 in 13 children in the United States. We are thrilled to see so many people embracing the Teal Pumpkin Project as a way to ensure kids with food allergies can enjoy a safe, fun Halloween experience just like their friends," says Veronica LaFemina, spokeswoman for Food Allergy Research &amp; Education. LaFemina says they are already starting to see photos of children with paintbrushes and teal pumpkins on doorsteps via Instagram and other social media channels. Families who are managing other diseases for which candy presents a problem, such as diabetes and celiac disease, have also shown support. If you don't want to purchase non-food items, it is helpful to separate allergy-free candy from candy that may trigger an allergic reaction if you're handing out goodies on October 31. Cross-contamination is a concern, as many food allergies require only a small amount of the allergen to trigger a reaction. No tricks this Halloween, just allergy-friendly treats Tips for parents Parents should also use extra caution when checking Halloween candy if their child has an allergy. "Checking labels becomes very pivotal because during the holidays, including Halloween, when the manufacturers make those mini small-sized candies and they're often mass-produced on shared equipment," says Mireille Schwartz, the founder and CEO of the Bay Area Allergy Advisory Board. "Candy that's safe other times of the year might not be safe during Halloween." Carrying an epinephrine auto-injector, which treats all anaphylaxis, is also a good safety measure. Schwartz recommends checking to see if the medication is up-to-date before leaving the house, as auto-injectors typically expire within one year. And while enjoying treats while walking door-to-door is a highlight of Halloween, it's best if parents make sure their child avoids the sweets until they can be inspected at home. For younger children, Schwartz adds, "You don't want to bring up the larger, darker side of things. You just want to say you're going to check the candy to make sure it's safe."</corpus>
        <section></section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Teal pumpkins try to change Halloween for kids with food allergies</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/health/halloween-safety-food-allergies/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141009104840-teal-pumpkin-project-halloween-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413202260000</timestamp>
        <author>Sara Cheshire</author>
        <corpus>Chocolate is frightening if you're allergic to milk, and a candy bar with nuts can be deadly. With eggs, soy and wheat also common allergies in kids, according to the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, finding treats without tricks can be a challenge on Halloween night. That's why the Food Allergy Research &amp; Education organization wants Halloween lovers to go teal this holiday. Their Teal Pumpkin Project encourages people to place a teal-painted pumpkin outside their door if they're offering non-foods treats, such as small toys, stickers and crayons. A flyer can also be printed from the website. The idea is taking off online. Food Allergy Research &amp; Education's first Facebook post about the Teal Pumpkin Project, reached 2.7 million people in less than 72 hours, the organization reported. Posts about the project have been shared a combined 31,000 times. This year marks the first time the idea has been promoted nationally. "The Teal Pumpkin Project is an easy way to make a big impact in your community. Food allergies can be life-threatening, and they affect 1 in 13 children in the United States. We are thrilled to see so many people embracing the Teal Pumpkin Project as a way to ensure kids with food allergies can enjoy a safe, fun Halloween experience just like their friends," says Veronica LaFemina, spokeswoman for Food Allergy Research &amp; Education. LaFemina says they are already starting to see photos of children with paintbrushes and teal pumpkins on doorsteps via Instagram and other social media channels. Families who are managing other diseases for which candy presents a problem, such as diabetes and celiac disease, have also shown support. If you don't want to purchase non-food items, it is helpful to separate allergy-free candy from candy that may trigger an allergic reaction if you're handing out goodies on October 31. Cross-contamination is a concern, as many food allergies require only a small amount of the allergen to trigger a reaction. No tricks this Halloween, just allergy-friendly treats Tips for parents Parents should also use extra caution when checking Halloween candy if their child has an allergy. "Checking labels becomes very pivotal because during the holidays, including Halloween, when the manufacturers make those mini small-sized candies and they're often mass-produced on shared equipment," says Mireille Schwartz, the founder and CEO of the Bay Area Allergy Advisory Board. "Candy that's safe other times of the year might not be safe during Halloween." Carrying an epinephrine auto-injector, which treats all anaphylaxis, is also a good safety measure. Schwartz recommends checking to see if the medication is up-to-date before leaving the house, as auto-injectors typically expire within one year. And while enjoying treats while walking door-to-door is a highlight of Halloween, it's best if parents make sure their child avoids the sweets until they can be inspected at home. For younger children, Schwartz adds, "You don't want to bring up the larger, darker side of things. You just want to say you're going to check the candy to make sure it's safe."</corpus>
        <section></section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Vietnam vet's prosthetic leg stolen at Philadelphia Eagles game</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/health/eagles-prosthetic-leg-stolen/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141013074640-philadelphia-eagles-giants-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413199800000</timestamp>
        <author>Jacque Wilson</author>
        <corpus>Police in Philadelphia are looking for a woman who allegedly ran off with Sonny Forriest Jr.'s fake limb outside Lincoln Financial Field during the Eagles game on Sunday night. Forriest often entertains Eagles fans with his singing outside the stadium, according to CNN affiliate WPVI. Forriest told police that he took off his leg because it was hurting him. It was on his chair when an intoxicated woman who appeared to be in her 20s grabbed it and ran off. She was dressed like an Eagles fan, Forriest told WPVI. "She said, 'I will pay you for it.' I said, 'That's all right, baby, go ahead and have a good time,' and then she disappeared," Forriest said. This isn't the first time Philadelphia sports fans have ended up in the news for odd behavior. In fact, city officials installed a courtroom in the old Eagles' stadium in the late 1990s just to sentence unruly fans. In April 2010, a Phillies fan intentionally vomited on a dad and his daughter. In 2000, a Philadelphia Flyers fan ended up in the hockey team's penalty box with enforcer Tie Domi. And who could forget what could be the largest one-sided snowball fight in history, when Eagles fans pelted the Dallas Cowboys team in 1989? WPVI reports that police found Forriest's prosthetic leg on a subway train about midnight Monday. No arrests have been made in the case. At least Forriest's team won: The Philadelphia Eagles beat the New York Giants, 27-0.</corpus>
        <section></section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Vietnam vet's prosthetic leg stolen at Philadelphia Eagles game</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/health/eagles-prosthetic-leg-stolen/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141013074640-philadelphia-eagles-giants-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413199800000</timestamp>
        <author>Jacque Wilson</author>
        <corpus>Police in Philadelphia are looking for a woman who allegedly ran off with Sonny Forriest Jr.'s fake limb outside Lincoln Financial Field during the Eagles game on Sunday night. Forriest often entertains Eagles fans with his singing outside the stadium, according to CNN affiliate WPVI. Forriest told police that he took off his leg because it was hurting him. It was on his chair when an intoxicated woman who appeared to be in her 20s grabbed it and ran off. She was dressed like an Eagles fan, Forriest told WPVI. "She said, 'I will pay you for it.' I said, 'That's all right, baby, go ahead and have a good time,' and then she disappeared," Forriest said. This isn't the first time Philadelphia sports fans have ended up in the news for odd behavior. In fact, city officials installed a courtroom in the old Eagles' stadium in the late 1990s just to sentence unruly fans. In April 2010, a Phillies fan intentionally vomited on a dad and his daughter. In 2000, a Philadelphia Flyers fan ended up in the hockey team's penalty box with enforcer Tie Domi. And who could forget what could be the largest one-sided snowball fight in history, when Eagles fans pelted the Dallas Cowboys team in 1989? WPVI reports that police found Forriest's prosthetic leg on a subway train about midnight Monday. No arrests have been made in the case. At least Forriest's team won: The Philadelphia Eagles beat the New York Giants, 27-0.</corpus>
        <section></section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Family waits with anger and hope: Is daughter's death linked to latest case?</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/us/virginia-murdered-daughter-familiy/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140930221925-exp-erin-dnt-casarez-virginia-missing-women-dna-link-00005026-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413138360000</timestamp>
        <author>Moni Basu</author>
        <corpus>Even for the people in the historically black Tinbridge Hill neighborhood of Lynchburg, where sense of community and oral history thrive, memories of Morton are hazy. "Wasn't she the girl whose body they found up on the mountain?" people ask. Morton went missing on October 10, 2009. Several weeks later, a hiker discovered the 23-year-old's decomposed body on Candlers Mountain, near Camp Hydaway, a retreat owned by Jerry Falwell's Liberty University. Lynchburg police and the Campbell County Sheriff's Office hunted for Morton's killer in vain. A year after her death, authorities admitted their leads had gone cold. As the years wore on, Morton's family learned to live without knowing who committed this heinous act. Or why she was robbed of life. Their hope of learning the truth diminished with time. Until recently. One night last month, University of Virginia student Hannah Graham disappeared after going out with friends. The arrest of a suspect in that case has prompted authorities to take another look at Morton's death and several other unsolved cases of women who were murdered, raped or went missing. Police have charged Jesse L. Matthew Jr. with abduction with the intent to defile in Graham's disappearance. They said forensic evidence also links Matthew to at least two other cases: the death of Morgan Harrington, whose body was discovered in Albemarle County in 2010, and a 2005 rape of a 26-year-old woman in Fairfax City. Matthew was also accused of a 2002 rape at Liberty University in Lynchburg, though charges were not pressed. The Campbell County Sheriff 's Office is investigating any possible connection between Matthew and Morton. Sheriff Steve Hutcherson declined further comment on an ongoing investigation. The result of all this has been that suddenly, almost five years after her death, Morton's face is all over the media again. It has meant torture, all over again, for her mother, Catherine Morton. She again felt the kind of shock that jolted her when police showed up at her doorstep several days after Thanksgiving 2009. They showed her a photograph of the body. She recognized her daughter's moccasins and beige jacket. They told her they had matched Cassandra's dental records to the body that was discovered. Catherine fell to the floor. "She hasn't been right ever since," says her husband and Cassandra's stepfather, Rawleigh Myers. Police seize cab of man linked to 2009 death Overshadowed by a 'damsel in distress'? Cassandra Morton's cremated remains rest in an urn her mother keeps by her bed. It's a constant reminder of the daughter she lost; a reminder that her killer remains unpunished. Every morning, Catherine Morton prays for her daughter's soul. She takes comfort in knowing that 250 people showed up at her daughter's funeral at the Tree of Life Ministries a few blocks up the road from her rented duplex on Campbell Avenue. She swallows eight or nine pills a day to treat her depression and hypertension. There's not much she can do about the anger that rises within. Why did her daughter's death not make national headlines like Graham or Harrington? Why did no one from the state come to help her in her hour of grief and pain? Morton's death was never big news. And it was always overshadowed by news about Harrington, who went missing six days after Morton vanished. In fact, when Morton's body was discovered, some headlines wondered if it might be that of Harrington, whose parents had been vocal from the first day about their daughter's strange disappearance from a Metallica concert at the University of Virginia campus in Charlottesville. They appeared on television and created a website to seek justice for their daughter. "There's been so much publicity about Morgan, about Hannah," Myers says. He is blind in his left eye and suffers from high blood pressure. He used to work for the school system, then performed odd jobs here and there. But these days, he and Catherine Morton barely survive by collecting disability. "The Harringtons can afford a reward to find their daughter's killer," he says, sitting on a small front porch cluttered with things. "We're poor and black. Nobody cares." His stepdaughter, Myers says, didn't fit the profile of missing women who make headlines. Like Elizabeth Smart, Laci Peterson and Natalee Holloway. Or Harrington and Graham. "It's hard to deny that race has something to do with the fact that attractive young white women get vastly more coverage when they disappear," says A. Barton Hinkle, an editorial writer at the Richmond Times-Dispatch, who wrote about the so-called Missing White Woman Syndrome in a recent column. The Washington Post's Eugene Robinson first described the media fascination in a 2005 column in which he described "Damsels in Distress." "A damsel must be white. This requirement is nonnegotiable. It helps if her frame is of dimensions that breathless cable television reporters can credibly describe as 'petite,' and it also helps if she's the kind of woman who wouldn't really mind being called 'petite,' a woman with a good deal of princess in her personality. She must be attractive -- also nonnegotiable. Her economic status should be middle class or higher, but an exception can be made in the case of wartime. "Put all this together, and you get 24-7 coverage," Robinson wrote. "The disappearance of a man, or of a woman of color, can generate a brief flurry, but never the full damsel treatment." Similar comments were made in Cleveland, after the bodies of 11 black women were found in a "house of horrors" in 2009. "In all their coverage, sympathetic as it may be, the [Cleveland] Plain Dealer never raises the bigger issue. What made these women such easy targets was being black, being women and being from the highly segregated and desperately poor east side of Cleveland," Angie Schmitt, founding editor of Rust Wire, wrote a year after the bodies were discovered. "Nobody was going to tear up the city looking for a few black women from the east side with sketchy pasts." Justice for everyone? Morton grew up in and around Lynchburg one of three siblings. Her parents separated, and when Catherine Morton married Myers about 12 years ago, he embraced her as his own. Myers never had much contact with his own daughter from a previous relationship; Cassandra filled that void. He loved to hear her call him "Daddy." Myers adjusts the baseball cap hugging his head. "Relax," it says. "God is in control." But he is far from relaxed talking about Cassandra. Catherine Morton decided she had had enough of journalists after Graham's case made the news. She had agreed to speak with me but changed her mind. She makes it clear she's upset her daughter's name has been dredged up again. She tells her husband to "keep it short." But Meyers wants to talk. He wants to keep Cassandra's memory alive. At a vigil last year organized by "Help Save The Next Girl," a group started by Harrington's parents, Myers spoke publicly about Cassandra. "She was loved," he told the crowd, among them the families of nine Virginia women whose cases remain unresolved. Myers says his stepdaughter wasn't perfect. She had fallen in and out of trouble, moved from one home to another. She was arrested in 2005 for theft. The photo that was used in newspapers and television when she went missing was, ironically, a police mug shot. She dabbled with drugs and men, Meyers says. She got pregnant and gave birth to two daughters. She was supposed to check into a rehabilitation facility two days after she went missing. She did not fit the picture of the all-American girl next door. But that, says her family, doesn't mean she should go without justice. Authorities have not said anything about the evidence they have on Matthew. Cassandra Morton's family has no idea whether she, Hannah Graham and Morgan Harrington are linked in some chilling way. They know only this: For the first time in years, they harbor hope again of learning the truth, however brutal that might be.</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Family waits with anger and hope: Is daughter's death linked to latest case?</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/us/virginia-murdered-daughter-familiy/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140930221925-exp-erin-dnt-casarez-virginia-missing-women-dna-link-00005026-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413138360000</timestamp>
        <author>Moni Basu</author>
        <corpus>Even for the people in the historically black Tinbridge Hill neighborhood of Lynchburg, where sense of community and oral history thrive, memories of Morton are hazy. "Wasn't she the girl whose body they found up on the mountain?" people ask. Morton went missing on October 10, 2009. Several weeks later, a hiker discovered the 23-year-old's decomposed body on Candlers Mountain, near Camp Hydaway, a retreat owned by Jerry Falwell's Liberty University. Lynchburg police and the Campbell County Sheriff's Office hunted for Morton's killer in vain. A year after her death, authorities admitted their leads had gone cold. As the years wore on, Morton's family learned to live without knowing who committed this heinous act. Or why she was robbed of life. Their hope of learning the truth diminished with time. Until recently. One night last month, University of Virginia student Hannah Graham disappeared after going out with friends. The arrest of a suspect in that case has prompted authorities to take another look at Morton's death and several other unsolved cases of women who were murdered, raped or went missing. Police have charged Jesse L. Matthew Jr. with abduction with the intent to defile in Graham's disappearance. They said forensic evidence also links Matthew to at least two other cases: the death of Morgan Harrington, whose body was discovered in Albemarle County in 2010, and a 2005 rape of a 26-year-old woman in Fairfax City. Matthew was also accused of a 2002 rape at Liberty University in Lynchburg, though charges were not pressed. The Campbell County Sheriff 's Office is investigating any possible connection between Matthew and Morton. Sheriff Steve Hutcherson declined further comment on an ongoing investigation. The result of all this has been that suddenly, almost five years after her death, Morton's face is all over the media again. It has meant torture, all over again, for her mother, Catherine Morton. She again felt the kind of shock that jolted her when police showed up at her doorstep several days after Thanksgiving 2009. They showed her a photograph of the body. She recognized her daughter's moccasins and beige jacket. They told her they had matched Cassandra's dental records to the body that was discovered. Catherine fell to the floor. "She hasn't been right ever since," says her husband and Cassandra's stepfather, Rawleigh Myers. Police seize cab of man linked to 2009 death Overshadowed by a 'damsel in distress'? Cassandra Morton's cremated remains rest in an urn her mother keeps by her bed. It's a constant reminder of the daughter she lost; a reminder that her killer remains unpunished. Every morning, Catherine Morton prays for her daughter's soul. She takes comfort in knowing that 250 people showed up at her daughter's funeral at the Tree of Life Ministries a few blocks up the road from her rented duplex on Campbell Avenue. She swallows eight or nine pills a day to treat her depression and hypertension. There's not much she can do about the anger that rises within. Why did her daughter's death not make national headlines like Graham or Harrington? Why did no one from the state come to help her in her hour of grief and pain? Morton's death was never big news. And it was always overshadowed by news about Harrington, who went missing six days after Morton vanished. In fact, when Morton's body was discovered, some headlines wondered if it might be that of Harrington, whose parents had been vocal from the first day about their daughter's strange disappearance from a Metallica concert at the University of Virginia campus in Charlottesville. They appeared on television and created a website to seek justice for their daughter. "There's been so much publicity about Morgan, about Hannah," Myers says. He is blind in his left eye and suffers from high blood pressure. He used to work for the school system, then performed odd jobs here and there. But these days, he and Catherine Morton barely survive by collecting disability. "The Harringtons can afford a reward to find their daughter's killer," he says, sitting on a small front porch cluttered with things. "We're poor and black. Nobody cares." His stepdaughter, Myers says, didn't fit the profile of missing women who make headlines. Like Elizabeth Smart, Laci Peterson and Natalee Holloway. Or Harrington and Graham. "It's hard to deny that race has something to do with the fact that attractive young white women get vastly more coverage when they disappear," says A. Barton Hinkle, an editorial writer at the Richmond Times-Dispatch, who wrote about the so-called Missing White Woman Syndrome in a recent column. The Washington Post's Eugene Robinson first described the media fascination in a 2005 column in which he described "Damsels in Distress." "A damsel must be white. This requirement is nonnegotiable. It helps if her frame is of dimensions that breathless cable television reporters can credibly describe as 'petite,' and it also helps if she's the kind of woman who wouldn't really mind being called 'petite,' a woman with a good deal of princess in her personality. She must be attractive -- also nonnegotiable. Her economic status should be middle class or higher, but an exception can be made in the case of wartime. "Put all this together, and you get 24-7 coverage," Robinson wrote. "The disappearance of a man, or of a woman of color, can generate a brief flurry, but never the full damsel treatment." Similar comments were made in Cleveland, after the bodies of 11 black women were found in a "house of horrors" in 2009. "In all their coverage, sympathetic as it may be, the [Cleveland] Plain Dealer never raises the bigger issue. What made these women such easy targets was being black, being women and being from the highly segregated and desperately poor east side of Cleveland," Angie Schmitt, founding editor of Rust Wire, wrote a year after the bodies were discovered. "Nobody was going to tear up the city looking for a few black women from the east side with sketchy pasts." Justice for everyone? Morton grew up in and around Lynchburg one of three siblings. Her parents separated, and when Catherine Morton married Myers about 12 years ago, he embraced her as his own. Myers never had much contact with his own daughter from a previous relationship; Cassandra filled that void. He loved to hear her call him "Daddy." Myers adjusts the baseball cap hugging his head. "Relax," it says. "God is in control." But he is far from relaxed talking about Cassandra. Catherine Morton decided she had had enough of journalists after Graham's case made the news. She had agreed to speak with me but changed her mind. She makes it clear she's upset her daughter's name has been dredged up again. She tells her husband to "keep it short." But Meyers wants to talk. He wants to keep Cassandra's memory alive. At a vigil last year organized by "Help Save The Next Girl," a group started by Harrington's parents, Myers spoke publicly about Cassandra. "She was loved," he told the crowd, among them the families of nine Virginia women whose cases remain unresolved. Myers says his stepdaughter wasn't perfect. She had fallen in and out of trouble, moved from one home to another. She was arrested in 2005 for theft. The photo that was used in newspapers and television when she went missing was, ironically, a police mug shot. She dabbled with drugs and men, Meyers says. She got pregnant and gave birth to two daughters. She was supposed to check into a rehabilitation facility two days after she went missing. She did not fit the picture of the all-American girl next door. But that, says her family, doesn't mean she should go without justice. Authorities have not said anything about the evidence they have on Matthew. Cassandra Morton's family has no idea whether she, Hannah Graham and Morgan Harrington are linked in some chilling way. They know only this: For the first time in years, they harbor hope again of learning the truth, however brutal that might be.</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Teen killed after haunted hayride in Maine flips over</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/us/maine-hayride-accident/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141012004542-hayride-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413155700000</timestamp>
        <author>Anne Woolsey</author>
        <author>Catherine E. Shoichet</author>
        <corpus>The teen was airlifted to a hospital after the accident Saturday night, Central Maine Medical Center spokesman Chuck Gill said. More than 20 other people were injured, CNN affiliate WMTW reported. The accident happened during what's called The Gauntlet, a spooky hayride through forest that includes "things that jump and scream in the night." The activity is part of Pumpkin Land, a venue featuring a variety of Halloween-themed activities in Mechanic Falls, about 30 miles north of Portland. The 17-year-old who died was on the ride with other students from Messalonskee High School in Oakland, Maine, according to WMTW. Investigators say they think a mechanical problem prevented a Jeep that was towing a tractor-trailer from stopping, WMTW reported, citing the state fire marshal's office. The Jeep went off the road, careened down a hill and slammed into a tree in a heavily wooded area around 8:30 p.m. Saturday, the CNN affiliate said. Authorities have impounded the Jeep and are investigating what caused the crash.</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Child who fell into jaguar exhibit at Arkansas Zoo is in stable condition</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/11/us/child-injured-zoo/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141011041931-dnt-toddler-falls-into-jaguar-exhibit-00000502-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413129240000</timestamp>
        <author>Azadeh Ansari</author>
        <author>Joshua Berlinger</author>
        <corpus>The 3-year-old boy's condition has been updated from critical to stable, according to a press release from Arkansas Children's Hospital obtained by CNN affiliate KARK. The child, who is not being named, is expected to improve. "We respect the wishes of the child's guardian, who asked that the child's name and any additional information not be shared at this time," said Dan McFadden, director of communications for the hospital. Witnesses say screams for help rang out loudly after the 3-year-old boy slipped through the exhibit rail feet first, plummeting into the cat pit, according to a Little Rock police report. The child was with his father and grandfather at the time of the incident. The father told Little Rock police he was leaning over the rail in an attempt to take a photograph of the animals and observed his son's feet go over the rail out of his peripheral vision. The child's grandfather says the little boy fell approximately 15-16 feet, police said. Two jaguars in the enclosure attacked the toddler. "The black cat had bit the child on the foot area and the yellow jaguar had bit the clothing near the neck area," read the police report, quoting the grandfather. Fire extinguishers were used to ward off the big cats in the exhibit, while a zookeeper lowered a ladder, climbed into the cat pit and retrieved the child, according to a statement released by the zoo. Zookeepers said the rescued child was conscious and responding. Though doctors said the wounds are not life-threatening, the toddler had an extensive scalp laceration, a depressed skull fracture and minor puncture wounds, according to the police report. "Our thoughts and prayers are with the child and the family. The safety of our citizens is of paramount value and our staff followed training procedures on rescuing the child and were able to respond quickly and efficiently and work with emergency personnel, said Bruce Moore, Little Rock city manager, in a statement. City officials said a full investigation into the incident is being conducted. Family settles lawsuit in mauling death of boy at Pittsburgh Zoo</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Judge overturns Alaska's same-sex marriage ban that dates to 1998</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/us/alaska-same-sex-marriage/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141011141826-north-carolina-same-sex-restricted-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413197100000</timestamp>
        <author>Saeed Ahmed</author>
        <corpus>On Sunday, a federal judge overturned the 16-year ban, saying the Constitution guarantees equal protection to all. The judge's ruling makes Alaska the latest state where gay and lesbian couples can legally marry. "The plaintiffs in this case do not ask the court to recognize an entirely new fundamental right to same-sex marriage; rather, plaintiffs wish to participate in the existing liberty granted to other couples to make a deeply personal choice about a private family matter," U.S. District Judge Timothy Burgess wrote in his 25-page ruling. Alaska says it will appeal. "As Alaska's governor, I have a duty to defend and uphold the law and the Alaska Constitution," Gov. Sean Parnell said. But how much luck the state will have going that route remains to be seen. An appeal will take the case to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, which last week ruled against Idaho and Nevada in similar cases. First-in-the-nation ban Alaska passed its amendment in 1998 and joined Hawaii as the first of two states to define marriage as a union between a man and a woman. At the time, Alaska said the ban "does not target anybody or deny anybody their rights." Burgess said it does. "By singling out homosexual couples and banning their ability to marry an individual of their choosing, it is impossible to assert that all Alaskans are equal under the state's laws." Five gay couples sued the state in May to get the constitutional amendment overturned. Another victory Sunday's ruling is yet another victory for supporters of same-sex marriage. In a surprise move on October 6, the Supreme Court refused to get involved in the constitutional debate over same-sex marriage. That decision allowed same-sex couples to wed legally in five states -- Virginia, Utah, Oklahoma, Indiana and Wisconsin. Then, a three-judge panel from the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit concluded the bans in Idaho and Nevada violated the equal protection rights of homosexuals to legally marry. On Friday, a federal judge in North Carolina ruled that same-sex marriage can begin there. "Alaska had the misfortune of being the first state, in 1998, to ban equal marriage and bake discrimination into our constitution," said Joshua Decker, executive director of the Alaska ACLU. "Today's decision allows Alaskans to marry and to have their outside marriages recognized here. This victory brings equal rights to thousands of Alaskan couples who are in loving, committed relationships." Like dominoes falling Here's where things stand. At least 27 states now allow same-sex marriage -- an increase of at least 13 states since the beginning of the month. Those states are: California, Colorado, Connecticut, Delaware, Hawaii, Idaho, Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Minnesota, Nevada, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, Oklahoma, Oregon, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Utah, Vermont, Virginia, Washington state and Wisconsin, plus the District of Columbia. Eight more states, including Alaska, could soon legalize it, after the cases wind their way through the federal appeals process: Alaska, Arizona, Kansas, North Carolina, Montana, South Carolina, West Virginia and Wyoming.</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>California drought victims drink in grandmother's kindness</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/11/us/california-drought-homes-without-running-water/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140906185326-01-gallegos-ca-drought-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413051000000</timestamp>
        <author>Michael Martinez,</author>
        <author>Sara Sidner</author>
        <author>Traci Tamura,</author>
        <corpus>The Central Valley farming community of East Porterville is a place where 400 homes are without running water. No showers. No flushing toilets. No way to wash dishes. That's because private wells have run dry. Turning the spigot is a futile exercise. "At first, it was dread that came over us. What are we going to do?" said Tony Alvarez, 62, a father of five whose home has been without water for weeks. "We are a low-income family. Things are hard enough as it is, trying to get everybody to school and get everybody ready." The worst of the drought is tormenting the Tulare County community 160 miles north of downtown Los Angeles. In East Porterville, drinking water comes from private wells, not public utilities. Of the community's 7,300 residents, nearly 1,000 are without running water, county officials said. Into this void has stepped a 71-year-old grandmother who saw a need and responded. She started by buying bottled water with her own money and delivering it to a list of people -- which just kept getting longer. 'An angel' What began as a mission of charity by Donna Johnson, a retiree, is now a well-publicized relief effort, inspiring businesses and others to donate bottled water. "She has a big heart. She's an angel," resident Angelica Gallegos said of Johnson. Johnson regularly visits Gallegos' door to ensure that she, her 5- and 10-year-old girls and husband have enough water for the week, Gallegos said. Johnson does the same for the elderly, the sick and anyone who needs it. She interrupted her retirement when she discovered just how many of her neighbors were living without running water. "So many people were not informed of what to do in a drought like this. I thought there are people who don't speak English, people that are elderly, they're pregnant, have diabetes, that are ill, everyday people. It doesn't have any prejudice. It affects everybody from the low-income to the higher-income person," Johnson said. State of emergency Johnson's humanitarian project comes as 100% of California faces at least a moderate drought and more than half of the state faces the worst category of dryness, called an exceptional drought, the U.S. Drought Monitor says. California isn't the only state feeling an absence of rain. As of late September, 30% of the Lower 48 faced at least a moderate drought, particularly in the Southwest states neighboring California and in Texas, the Drought Monitor says. But none of those states is facing the extremes of California, where the drought has been a slowly building natural disaster since 2012. In fact, Gov. Jerry Brown this year declared a state emergency, saying his constituents are facing "perhaps the worst drought that California has ever seen since records (began) about 100 years ago." On September 16, Brown signed "historic legislation" that creates "a framework for sustainable, local groundwater management for the first time in California history," the governor's office said. Before the new legislation, California was the only Western state that didn't manage its groundwater, officials said. In the meantime, dramatic struggles and responses are unfolding in communities like East Porterville, whose new heroine is receiving national attention. With one jug of water in each arm, Johnson moves at a frantic pace through the dust and often 100-degree heat to deliver drinking water to as many people as possible, as fast as she can. She is now assisted by Matt Rogers, her 19-year-old neighbor who saw how she helps people suffering from the drought. "It's almost like an illness. It kind of spreads and all of a sudden it's a catastrophe, and it is a disaster," Johnson said. Ahead of officials Without Johnson's effort, officials say they would not have known just how many people were hurting. "She really helped raise awareness about how bad it was in this confined area," Tulare County Emergency Services Manager Andrew Lockman said. Many residents never thought the drought could so profoundly alter their lives. "You never expect it and you never want to live through this. It's really hard," 17-year-old Sandra Tapia said as Johnson delivered water. Her father, a field hand, came home one day in August and discovered there was no running water for his family of six. "You can't go to the bathroom, you can't take a shower, you can't wash dishes. You have to conserve every single drop," Tapia said. Officials say they value Johnson's bringing attention to the disaster because some residents simply don't know what would happen if they told authorities about their lack of running water. Community in fear For example, some residents worried the government would red-tag their homes and make them move. Migrant workers worried their landlords would kick them out if they reported the problem. Undocumented immigrants panicked about being deported if they had contact with authorities. Authorities sought to soothe those suspicions and fears. "We're not here to make things worse," Lockman said. The 400 private wells without water in East Porterville are just a fraction of the 30,000 private wells throughout Tulare County, which also includes portions of the Sierra Nevada and the Sequoia and Kings Canyon national parks, officials said. As distressing as the empty wells are, officials are also concerned it will take a long time to restore all of them, whether empty or low. "The issue is we still expect this to get worse, even if we get a substantial rainfall this winter. A lot of the areas in the county are going to take a year or two years to recharge their water levels," Lockman added. There is no quick fix. A grandmother weeps Homes with private wells aren't hooked up to water mains, and such a connection could take years, officials said. The original deal was that residents with private wells would not get a water bill but were responsible for maintaining the wells. That became a problem in the drought because many residents can't afford the thousands of dollars it takes to drill a deeper well. Moreover, even if residents have the money, there is up to a two-year backlog to hire a company to do the job, officials said. In the meantime, county officials are helping residents secure grants for delivery of commercial bottled water. For now, the county is offering a 5,000-gallon tank of water outside the local fire department. Residents can't use that water to drink or wash dishes because it's not potable, but they can use it for toilets, baths and laundry. Residents show up not just with buckets but 55-gallon drums. On a recent afternoon, as he filled up several jugs of water, Alvarez, the father of five whose home has been without water for weeks, called the tank a real help, but he worried about folks who don't have transportation and are out of water. That is where Johnson comes in. At first, she bought the bottled water with her own money and delivered it herself, but now she enjoys donations of bottled water and help from the young neighbor who was inspired by her work. She labors voluntarily through the heat three days a week, but the demands of one recent day proved to be overwhelming: Johnson broke down in tears, feeling the depths of the insidious disaster. She finds comfort in her work, though. That's because her private well has run dry, too, and she savors the kindness of donations. "Without water, you can't survive, you can't keep your home and you can't keep water in it, and my heart goes out to everybody," she said.</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Ferguson protests: Weekend of protests, day of action</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/us/ferguson-protests/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141011052748-pkg-sidner-missouri-protests-00001707-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413197040000</timestamp>
        <author>Sara Sidner,</author>
        <corpus>Demonstrators demanding the arrest of the police officer who killed Michael Brown say they will take part in a "series of actions" Monday morning, but they haven't said what or where those will be. Sunday night, about 2,000 people attended an interfaith rally, where activist and Princeton University professor Cornel West was the featured speaker. Before he took the stage at the St. Louis University's Chaifetz Arena, some protesters demanded for a chance to speak. "If you can see a dead black boy lie in the streets for four hours and that doesn't make you angry you lack humanity," a woman, who didn't give her name, told the crowd. She was referring to how long the body of Brown lay on the street before investigating officers removed it. The protests, dubbed a "Ferguson October" and "Weekend of Resistance," are taking place in Ferguson, St. Louis and the surrounding area. Demonstrations focused on the August 9 encounter between Brown, 18, and Police Officer Darren Wilson, who authorities said shot Brown after he attacked him and tried to take his gun. Mom, daughter trek 750 miles on $100 budget to join 'Weekend of Resistance' But witnesses said the unarmed teenager had his hands in the air when he was shot. The shooting prompted weeks of protests in Ferguson, which sometimes became violent when demonstrators and police clashed. The demonstrators are demanding that Wilson be charged with a crime -- a point that West also made. . "Everybody knows if you shoot somebody down, you should be arrested," he said. He asked the crowd to channel their rage into a plan of action for change. Before this week, protests had died down considerably. But early Sunday, protesters threw rocks at police and tried to storm a QuikTrip store early Sunday, according to tweets from St. Louis Police Chief Sam Dotson, Twelve miles away in Shaw, St. Louis, protesters have also rallied against the death of Vonderrit Deondre Myers, 18. Protests erupted there after a white police officer fatally shot the black teenager. But this one was different from the Brown case because the teenager was armed and fired at the officer, according to authorities. Early Monday morning, about 200 protesters marched from the site where Myers was shot, holding signs that read, "Black lives matter." Police with riot gear showed up on a bridge near the St. Louis university campus. The protestors turned on the other side of the street, stayed on the sidewalk and walked past them. The demonstrations were peaceful, and the protesters said they were serious in keeping it that way.</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Seven teens charged in Sayreville High School assaults</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/us/new-jersey-football-abuse-scandal/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141009230123-ctn-dnt-marquez-high-school-hazing-00014011-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1413006480000</timestamp>
        <author>Azadeh Ansari,</author>
        <corpus>Upperclassmen howled as they flipped off the lights then sexually abused their younger classmates at Sayreville High School, parents and players say. The identities of the teens, ranging in age from 15 to 17, are being withheld because of their ages, but the Middlesex County Prosecutor's Office released details of the charges in a statement Friday. A seventh teen also has been charged. "Three of the juvenile defendants are charged with aggravated sexual assault, aggravated criminal sexual contact, conspiracy to commit aggravated criminal sexual contact, criminal restraint, and hazing for engaging in an act of sexual penetration upon one of the juvenile victims," the release stated. "One of those juvenile defendants and the remaining four juvenile defendants were charged with various counts including aggravated assault, conspiracy, aggravated criminal sexual contact, hazing and riot by participating in the attack of the remaining victims." A family court will decide whether the six teens will be held at a detention facility pending a court hearing or will be released to the custody of their parents or guardians pending the hearing, the prosecutor's office also said in the press release. The coach and officials would not comment on details of the abuse, but it may have gone on for a year. A Sports Illustrated article indicated that it likely did not involve intercourse. "There were incidents of harassment, intimidation that took place on a pervasive level, in which the players knew, tolerated and in general accepted," says Superintendent Richard Labbe, who has canceled the successful team's football season. The Sayreville Bombers took the state championship three out of the last four years. Now parents used to watching their sons' spirited team reign victorious on the gridiron are upset the season won't continue. "I've never seen so much dedication out of my son, and I want him to play the rest of this season," a mother said at a school meeting to the roar of applause. Despondent players vented frustration over not being able to finish what they've started. They are at odds with parents and players who broke the allegations. That group is less vocal and declined to be interviewed on camera, afraid to voice grievances out loud. Parents on both sides have hired lawyers. A hearing date has not been determined, according to the Middlesex County Prosecutor's Office.</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>113-year-old time capsule found in Boston</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/us/boston-time-capsule/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141010165928-04-boston-time-capsule-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1412992320000</timestamp>
        <corpus>According to the Bostonian Society, which maintains the 1713-built Old Massachusetts State House, the rectangular copper box containing a variety of artifacts from 1901 was sealed inside one of two iconic statues -- a lion and a unicorn -- that have been a familiar site atop the Old State House for a couple of centuries. The Bostonian Society didn't -- or couldn't -- fully divulge the 113-year-old time capsule's contents, explaining that "the process of extracting documents that are old and probably fragile will need to be slow and careful." But a Boston Globe article from February 24, 1901, detailed what went into the box, which the story predicted would "prove interesting when the box is opened many years hence." According to the Globe, the box included the photographs and autographs of local statesmen such as Massachusetts Gov. Winthrop M. Crane and Boston Mayor Thomas Norton Hart, as well as news clippings of the day from several city newspapers and even a "letter to posterity from the reporters of the Boston Daily newspapers assigned to City Hall." It also included a photograph of the "5th Massachusetts Regiment on its way to Framingham to be mustered in as U.S. volunteers for service in the war against Spain," as well as "campaign buttons for McKinley, Roosevelt and John D. Long for vice president." The box was sealed inside the lion's head by Samuel Rogers, a local coppersmith who was part of the crew renovating the nearly 200-year-old State House. Although the occasion was detailed in the city's largest newspaper, the Bostonian Society said its current staff was unaware of the time capsule until they received a letter from a descendent of Rogers alerting them to it.</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Did Florida boys school officials send family a casket filled with wood?</title>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/09/us/pennsylvania-dozier-school-for-boys-exhumation/index.html</url>
        <image>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/121013123713-pkg-lavendera-marianna-boys-reform-school-graves-00004705-story-top.jpg</image>
        <timestamp>1412900640000</timestamp>
        <author>Eliott C. McLaughlin</author>
        <corpus>Curry was a charge of Marianna, Florida's Arthur G. Dozier School for Boys, a now infamous juvenile detention facility that closed in 2011 for budgetary reasons, capping a chilling, 111-year legacy of brutality. From 1900 to 1952, according to a court document, 100 boys died there, but only about half were buried on the reform institution's grounds. Others were shipped home to their families. Curry, 17, became part of that tally in 1925 when he died "under suspicious circumstances while escaping Dozier twenty-nine days after arriving," says the court order permitting his exhumation this week. The coroner at the time ruled Curry's manner of death was unknown. The ledger entry at the Dozier school said he was "killed on RR Bridge Chattahoochee, Fla." Another document at Old Cathedral Cemetery in Philadelphia says he was "killed by train." No one from Dozier ever reported his death to the state. He was returned in a casket to his family, who, in turn, buried him in Philadelphia. Or so the family thought. It wasn't until a state investigation beginning in 2008 that Curry's death certificate was found at Dozier. It said he died of a crushed skull from an "unknown cause." And it wasn't until Tuesday, when University of South Florida anthropologists who have been working to unearth and identify remains on the former campus visited Philadelphia with Pennsylvania authorities, that the family learned Curry wasn't in the casket -- no bones, no clothing, no sign of him at all. "Wood. Layers of pieces of wood," said anthropologist Erin Kimmerle, explaining what she and her team found in the casket. "It was completely filled with wooden planks." At first, the team thought they had the wrong grave, but then they found Curry's great-grandparents beneath the wood-filled casket. 'Decades of efforts to deceive' Kimmerle was still incredulous Wednesday, as was Cpl. Tom McAndrew of the Pennsylvania State Police, who along with Philadelphia Assistant District Attorney Brendan O'Malley, was instrumental in clearing the path for Kimmerle's team to exhume Curry's remains, she said, "It was a little bit of a shock. It was certainly anticlimactic," McAndrew said. "Something was shipped up from Florida, and it was buried, and someone believed it was Thomas Curry." Does he think, as a law enforcement officer, that the finding is indicative of school officials' intent to deceive Curry's family nine decades ago? "Absolutely," he said, but it's not surprising when you consider that the investigation into the Dozier school has uncovered "decades and decades of efforts to deceive, coverups, and not just by one but by many people." McAndrew has been in contact with two of Curry's distant cousins, and while they weren't familiar with Curry or his death before Kimmerle's team began investigating, they've done what they could to advance the investigation, the police corporal said. They've provided names from their family tree and handwritten notes from their mother. One of the cousins, Eileen Witmier, who is 61 and is the granddaughter of Curry's mom's sister, provided DNA to identify Curry -- had he been found. "Their interest lies in justice being served," McAndrew said of the cousins. Asked where his own interest lies, McAndrew gave a similar answer, but also noted that Kimmerle has been an invaluable ally to law enforcement. Quid pro quo among professionals The ex-chief anthropologist for the U.N. International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia, Kimmerle has conducted "isotope testing" in her lab to help McAndrew with homicide cases in Pennsylvania. For one particularly high-profile case -- a pregnant teen found dismembered in suitcases in 1976 -- Kimmerle's team analyzed the woman's hair and teeth. Via isotope testing, Kimmerle was able to determine where the woman lived based on the water she consumed while alive. Though police have yet to solve the case, they now know she was born in Europe and immigrated to the Southeastern United States at age 12, McAndrew said. "When she turned to me for assistance, obviously I would've done anything for her," McAndrew said of Kimmerle. Kimmerle had hoped, of course, that Curry's remains would unravel some of the mystery surrounding his death. "We went into it trying to answer questions," she said. "What we have is more questions than answers." But the investigation continues. Now armed with Witmier's DNA, Kimmerle's team can return to Marianna, about 65 miles west of Tallahassee, and attempt to match the sample to one of the dozens of bodies that have already been dug up on the 1,400-acre former campus. Though many of the boys died so long ago, it's important to find their family members, Kimmerle believes, if only because of the uncertainties surrounding their deaths and the controversy enveloping the supposed school where they died. A dubious legacy That bodies lay there was never a secret -- 31 rusty, white crosses marked the resting places of victims who died from a dormitory fire, influenza, pneumonia and other causes -- but Kimmerle's team has found a total of 55 bodies there so far. Her team also has found records indicating that 22 boys who died at the school are unaccounted for. Already, Kimmerle and her colleagues have identified three sets of remains. One of those bodies was George Owen Smith, whose sister Ovell Krell, 85, told CNN in August she was elated that the seven-decade mystery surrounding her brother's death was finally solved. Though ex-students provided detailed accounts of vicious beatings, sexual abuse and disappearances, guards and administrators who are still alive have denied the beatings occurred. The state investigation in 2008 and 2009 said there was insufficient evidence of abuse at Dozier, but dozens of men, many of them now senior citizens, have come forward with stories. A support group for ex-students, dubbed The White House Boys, takes its moniker from the structure where boys say they were beaten with a leather strap attached to a wooden handle. They were whipped until their underwear was embedded in their buttocks, The White House Boys say. Some were beaten unconscious. Crying or screaming out would earn you extra lashes, they say. So while this week's exhumation didn't answer any of the myriad questions surrounding Dozier and its missing and dead boys, it was still an important part of the ongoing investigation, researchers and police said. "It definitely had to be done," McAndrew said. "We had to at least open the grave if this investigation down in Florida is going to be resolved." Remains of 2 more boys identified at shuttered Florida reformatory</corpus>
        <section>U.S.</section>
    </article>
</news_list>

