<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<news_list>
    <article>
        <title>Turkish lawmakers OK military action against ISIS</title>
        <author>Laura Smith-Spark, Chelsea J. Carter  Gul Tuysuz</author>
        <corpus>The Turkish Parliament voted 298-98 to not only to let the country's military leave its borders to go after ISIS and other terror groups, but also allow foreign troops to launch operations from Turkey. The authorization takes effect Saturday. It is a big shift for Turkey, a NATO member, which until now offered only tacit support to a U.S.-led coalition of about 40 nations going after ISIS in Iraq and Syria in various capacities. The mood of Turkey's leaders changed in recent days, with ISIS on the nation's doorstep and tens of thousands fleeing across its border. The Prime Minister asked Parliament to consider military action this week, submitting a motion declaring that Turkey was seriously threatened by the chaos in Syria and Iraq, where ISIS has captured land and is trying to establish an Islamic caliphate. For months, ISIS has been advancing, capturing portions of northern and eastern Syria and western and northern Iraq for what it says is its new Islamic state, or caliphate. The fighting has only intensified in the region in recent days, with ISIS advancing and nearly surrounding the Syrian Kurdish city of Kobani, known in Arabic as Ayn al-Arab, just a few miles from the border with Turkey. If ISIS takes Kobani, it will control a complete swath of land from its self-declared capital of Raqqa on the Euphrates River to the Turkish border, more than 100 kilometers (60 miles) away. Residents told to evacuate Residents in Kobani were ordered to evacuate Thursday by the local defense force, the Kurdish People's Protection Unit (YPG), as ISIS advanced on three fronts, seizing a number of villages just outside the city, Mustafa Abdi, a media activist in the city, told CNN. Abdi said he was waiting at the border at Mursitpinar with approximately 3,000 people waiting to cross into Turkey. Saroat Saeed, a university student, said he had made it across the border after waiting with what he said were the last civilians to leave Kobani. Only fighters trying to defend the city now remain, he said, but it is surrounded by ISIS and they face a dire situation. Alan Minbic, a YPG fighter, said Kobani had now been declared a military zone by the Kurdish force's leaders. ISIS has Kobani surrounded from three sides and its fighters are positioned very close to the city, he said. Kurdish snipers have taken up positions on high ground around the city but can expect ISIS shelling to try to dislodge them, he said. The YPG is now expecting ISIS to try to enter the city itself, Minbic said, adding that guerrilla warfare is the best chance for the defenders of Kobani because they hold the city and know it well. 'We are not afraid to die' Another YPG fighter who gave only his first name, Botan, said from Kobani that the Kurdish forces were determined to fight on. &quot;ISIS has surrounded us but we will fight, we are keeping our morale high,&quot; he said. &quot;We know, we have also seen, what ISIS is capable of, what brutality they can do. ... We know what they can do but we are not afraid to die, we are not afraid to fight. We know what will happen if ISIS takes over our town and what they will do to us.&quot; The fighters will resist neighborhood by neighborhood, he said. &quot;Our fight is not just for the Kurds, it is a fight for all of humanity. When people are getting their heads chopped off and tossed aside like animals, it is a duty to fight.&quot; The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a London-based monitoring group, said Thursday that clashes had been reported between YPG and ISIS fighters only a few hundred yards from the east and southeast of the city. ISIS militants have seized more than 350 villages in the past 16 days and displaced no fewer than 300,000 people from Kobani and the surrounding countryside, it said. Many have taken to social media to ask why there has been seemingly little attention by the United States and its coalition partners paid to helping the Kurdish fighters in Kobani hold off ISIS. On Twitter, people are using hashtags #ObamaHearKobani and #SaveKobani as part of an effort to raise the question. There was at least one airstrike near Kobani on Thursday by the coalition, according to the U.S. military. The strike targeted an ISIS checkpoint near the town, the military said. Turkey's decision on military action came a day after newly appointed NATO chief Jens Stoltenberg stressed at his first news conference that the defense alliance was committed to protecting Turkey if it comes under attack. Special forces deployed A possible threat to an ancient tomb -- located in Syria but considered a Turkish enclave -- also appeared to be a factor in Turkey's decision to approve going after ISIS. Reports had emerged that ISIS surrounded the tomb of the grandfather of the founder of the Ottoman Empire. President Recep Tayyip Erdogan has dismissed reports that ISIS had surrounded the site. But the debate in Parliament mentioned increasing security risks to the white marble mausoleum. As part of the Treaty of Ankara in 1921, which ended the Franco-Turkish War, Turkey was allowed to keep the tomb despite its location in Syria, to place guards at it and to raise a Turkish flag over it. Opinion: Will Turkish boots on ground really defeat ISIS? There have been conflicting reports in recent days about what has happened at the tomb and its guards, with some claims emerging that ISIS fighters briefly took the guards captive. It has also been widely reported that ISIS has had the tomb surrounded for months. So valued is the tomb said to contain the remains of Suleyman Shah -- grandfather of Osman I, the founder of the Ottoman Empire -- that Turkey deployed special forces soldiers in March when ISIS began to take villages and towns surrounding the tomb. Allen: 'Important moment' for anti-ISIS coalition U.N. report details abuses While Turkey approved the use of military action against ISIS, a new United Nations report outlined &quot;a staggering array&quot; of human rights abuses committed by ISIS in Iraq over a nine-week period, including executions, killings, rape and the desecration of religious sites. The report documents &quot;acts of violence of an increasingly sectarian nature&quot; by ISIS and associated armed groups and says their abuses appear to be widespread and systematic. From women reportedly being shot in the head for refusing to treat ISIS fighters, to the execution of Sunnis who refused to swear allegiance to ISIS, to the suicide bombing of a Shia mosque, it's a litany of horrors. Produced jointly by the U.N. Assistance Mission for Iraq and the Office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights, the report covers the period from July 6 to September 10, when ISIS was advancing across a swath of northern Iraq. The abuses &quot;include attacks directly targeting civilians and civilian infrastructure, executions and other targeted killings of civilians, abductions, rape and other forms of sexual and physical violence perpetrated against women and children, forced recruitment of children, destruction or desecration of places of religious or cultural significance, wanton destruction and looting of property, and denial of fundamental freedoms,&quot; the report said. White House exempts ISIS strikes from civilian casualty guidelines</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Rio Ferdinand: Soccer authorities must get ruthless on racism</title>
        <author>Chris Murphy,</author>
        <corpus>The former England and Manchester United star also believes football's world and European governing bodies should consult current players when meting out punishments. Ferdinand, currently plying his trade for English Premier League strugglers Queens Park Rangers, thinks the game still has a long road to travel in what is proving an exhaustive and complex battle. The 35-year-old's brother Anton was at the center of one of the most high-profile English cases of recent times, when he accused Chelsea captain John Terry of racial abuse. Read: Ferdinand defends Ferguson And Ferdinand is resolute in his belief that the war on discrimination is one football cannot wage alone. &quot;There were a lot of campaigns that were going on over the years that I was a part of and I thought 'Yes. Football is doing a great job, especially in England,'&quot; Ferdinand told CNN. &quot;And then all of a sudden (the Terry case) made me realize that it was just put under the carpet a little bit and it was still there. But it made me realize that football can't be the tool that kind of eradicates racism. &quot;It's got to be a social element to it. Schools, parenting, education has got to play a bigger role in getting rid of racism. &quot;There has been progress but there's also been times where you think 'I thought we'd got past that.' &quot;I think sometimes the powers that be sometimes aren't ruthless enough in handing out punishments and that where I'd like there to be sometimes more dialogue maybe with people that are playing the game still -- people of different races to be in the decision making process as well. &quot;So that people who are making the decisions understand that it does hurt when these type of things happen on a football pitch or a stadium or around sports.&quot; Ferdinand cites the incident involving his brother and ex-England captain Terry, as well as former Liverpool striker Luis Suarez's eight-match ban for abusing Patrice Evra -- then of Manchester United -- as evidence that racism is still a major issue in today's game. Terry was found not guilty in court of abusing Anton Ferdinand during a Premier League match in October 2011 but the Football Association later banned him for four matches and fined him £220,000 ($355,000) on the same charge. Terry later apologized for the language he used. Ferdinand calls Terry &quot;an idiot&quot; in his autobiography #2sides in reference to the case and now thinks a conversation at the time might have helped heal some of the wounds. &quot;I do a whole chapter on the relationship between myself and John and my brother and, yes, I think that would have solved a lot of problems if there would've been a conversation, an apology, at the beginning,&quot; he explained. &quot;I think things might have gone a bit differently, but again the powers that be made a lot of decisions that we maybe didn't agree with at the time. &quot;That could've maybe had a different outcome to the whole situation if we were listened to. But, as I said, it's all stuff that I've had to go over and talk about in the book and it's been a bit of a healing process so to speak.&quot; Incidents of racism haven't been restricted to on-field events, with chants from fans also prompting soccer's authorities to issue sanctions. There have been a string of incidents over recent seasons, with CSKA Moscow's European Champions League tie with Bayern Munich on Tuesday held behind closed doors due to a racist incident in last season's competition. Brazilian club Gremio was banned from a cup competition in September after an opponent's goalkeeper was racially abused during a match. And Ferdinand thinks heftier fines would act as firm deterrent, with stadium bans dished out to repeat offenders. &quot;If it's going to be money, then it's got to be huge amounts,&quot; he explained. &quot;There's vast amounts of money in the game so it should be reflected in the punishment. &quot;If you're going to hand a Federation a £60,000 ($96,000) fine when that Federation's pulling in millions a year that is not going to hurt. So it's got to equate to what they generate I think. Or you ban them from playing in their home country. &quot;If you say to a country 'Listen you're not going to play your national games in your country now after what just happened in the stadium,' I think the fans will start thinking a bit differently. &quot;And as I said that doesn't stop racism. It just stops it in a stadium. &quot;So that's why I always talk about a bigger idea on racism and a social element rather than just football but it stops it in a stadium and hopefully that can be then hopefully replicated, maybe, in society.&quot; Much of the spotlight has centered on Russia, hosts of the 2018 World Cup. The country's football association was fined after its fans directed racist abuse at a Czech Republic player during Euro 2012. CSKA Moscow has twice been forced to play matches either behind closed doors or with part of its stadium shut due to racist incidents, one after Manchester City's Yaya Toure was subjected to monkey chants in October 2013. The most recent, against Bayern Munich this week, was in response to an incident during a match with Czech club Viktoria Plzen, also last season. But Ferdinand thinks countries should be given a chance to clean up their act, with Russia being no exception. &quot;Yes they've had issues in the past but I think they should be given that opportunity to rectify that,&quot; he said. &quot;There's no bigger event on the planet than the World Cup and this is a time they can cover themselves in some glory. &quot;That's down to their federation and the people that run their game to make sure that they put in place things to happen that if they do step out of line there's going to be big punishments and as I said, that's the only way that they can kind of rectify any mistakes they've made in the past.&quot; Ferdinand has been linked with a role within FIFA but says while he is always available to consult he is firmly focused on playing for the time being. &quot;No I'm not in the line for any of those positions to be honest with you,&quot; he added. &quot;I'm concentrating on playing football. I'm happy playing football. If they want a conversation about various things, I'm always here and willing to be speak. &quot;Once I retire then things like that maybe can be approached and looked upon but right now all my efforts are in trying to help QPR stay up in the Premier League.&quot; Read: Everything you need to know about Falcao Read: 'Come Home Ronaldo' beg Man Utd fans</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>William and Catherine warn paparazzi to back off Prince George</title>
        <author>Lindsay Isaac Laura Smith-Spark</author>
        <corpus>The two individuals have essentially been stalking Prince George, who is 14 months old, said a palace spokesman. William and Kate want their son, who is third in line to the British throne, to have &quot;as normal a childhood as possible,&quot; the spokesman said. The Duke and Duchess of Cambridge are grateful to the British press for refraining from publishing the paparazzi photos, he added. The letters were delivered &quot;earlier this week,&quot; the spokesman said. There has not yet been a response. Buckingham Palace spokesmen traditionally are not quoted by name. Catherine is expecting the couple's second child, royal officials confirmed last month, and as a result has canceled some public engagements. As during her first pregnancy, she is suffering from hyperemesis gravidarum, or acute morning sickness. The condition involves nausea and vomiting more severe than the typical morning sickness many women suffer during early pregnancy.</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Syria terror charges against Moazzam Begg dropped</title>
        <author>Laura Smith-Spark</author>
        <corpus>Begg, from Birmingham in the English Midlands, will now be freed from prison, where he has been held since March, a West Midlands Police statement said. The case was discontinued after police and lawyers for the Crown Prosecution Service reviewed new material and concluded there was no longer a realistic prospect of gaining a conviction, the statement said. Begg's trial had been due to start on October 6. Assistant Chief Constable Marcus Beale said: &quot;New material has recently been disclosed to police and CPS, which has a significant impact on key pieces of evidence that underpinned the prosecution's case. Our criminal justice system -- quite rightly -- demands a very high standard of proof. &quot;I understand this is going to raise many questions. However, explaining what this newly revealed information is would mean discussing other aspects of the case which would be unfair and inappropriate as they are no longer going to be tested in court.&quot; 'Testing time' Begg was charged with attending a terrorist training camp, facilitating terrorism and possession of a document likely to be of use to a terrorist. The London-based organization Cage, which campaigns for the rights of those affected by the &quot;war on terror&quot; and for which Begg worked as an outreach director, welcomed the decision to drop the charges. &quot;This has been a testing time for Moazzam, his family and the Muslim community,&quot; Asim Qureshi, research director of Cage, said in a statement. Qureshi accused UK authorities of criminalizing &quot;virtually any Muslim that has been to Syria&quot; and said Cage had also come under pressure to shut down. &quot;We hope that Moazzam's release is a sign that the government are now willing to adopt a more measured strategy in relation to anti-terrorism policy and avoid the attempt to criminalize all dissent and crush any organization like Cage that stands up for the rule of law and justice,&quot; he added. Author, speaker Begg was arrested as a suspected al Qaeda member in Pakistan in February 2002 and was held at the U.S. airbase at Bagram, Afghanistan, before being sent to the U.S. prison camp at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. Begg spent nearly three years in custody. He was sent back to Britain by the Bush administration in early 2005 and was never prosecuted. He co-authored a book about his experiences at Guantanamo Bay in 2006 and has appeared as a public speaker and commentator in Britain and overseas since his release.</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>ISIS closes in on Kurdish town in Syria; Turkey debates sending troops</title>
        <author>Chelsea J. Carter, Gul Tuysuz Ben Wedeman ,</author>
        <corpus>The flood of refugees from Syria has escalated -- with 150,000 people fleeing to Turkey in recent days -- as ISIS fighters armed with tanks and heavy weapons advance on the predominantly Kurdish town of Kobani, known in Arabic as Ayn al Arab, destroying villages in their path. ISIS fighters were just three kilometers (nearly two miles) east of the northern Syria town late Monday, a civilian in Kobani told CNN on condition of anonymity. CNN cannot independently confirm the claim, though it matches reports released by the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a monitoring group. U.S. airstrikes overnight targeted ISIS positions near Kobani, said Rear Adm. John Kirby, spokesman for the Pentagon. It was unclear whether the strikes stopped the ISIS advance, and Kirby provided only cursory details about what they targeted and what damage may have resulted. When asked why airstrikes in the Kobani area appear to be limited, a senior U.S. official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said a lack of direct, reliable intelligence on the ground and the need to be precise to avoid civilian casualties were among the factors. Poll: Americans back airstrikes, but oppose use of U.S. troops Turkey considers going after ISIS If ISIS takes Kobani, it would control a complete swath of land from its self-declared capital of Raqqa to the Turkish border, more than 100 kilometers (60 miles) away. It has been fighting for months, capturing portions of northern and eastern Syria and western and northern Iraq for what it says is its new Islamic state -- or caliphate. The Turkish Parliament on Tuesday took up the issue whether to send troops into Iraq and Syria to fight ISIS. The debate was expected to continue into the latter part of the week before lawmakers voted, according to Anadolu, Turkey's semi-official news agency. Turkey has said it is offering support to a U.S.-led coalition targeting ISIS, but has stopped short of joining the 40-some countries who make up the coalition. But with more than 150,000 refugees pouring into the country since last week, adding to the hundreds of thousands who have already fled the Syrian civil war, and concerns about ISIS controlling border points, Turkish lawmakers are taking up the issue. Obama assesses ISIS strategy At the same time, U.S. President Barack Obama met with his National Security Council to discuss what White House officials described as a comprehensive strategy to counter the threat posed by ISIS, also known as ISIL. The meeting follows Obama's admission on CBS' &quot;60 Minutes&quot; that the United States underestimated the strength of ISIS and overestimated the ability of the Iraqi security forces to fight the group. Nowhere was that assessment more evident than in reports ISIS had seized another Iraqi military base about 80 kilometers (50 miles) west of Baghdad over the weekend. Dozens of ISIS fighters attacked the Albu Aytha military base, north of Ramadi, where 180 Iraqi soldiers were stationed, according to Faleh al-Essawi, deputy head of the Anbar provincial council. ISIS has been fanning out across the Sunni-dominated Anbar region in recent months, targeting bases one by one across the vast area. Syrian town fears massacre; Obama admits underestimating rise of ISIS About a week ago, details emerged regarding the massacre of more than 100 Iraqi soldiers at bases in Saqlawiyah and Sejar, also near Ramadi. A handful of survivors accused the Iraqi government of failing to respond to pleas for help ahead of the final ISIS assault on the base, after a dayslong siege. ISIS overruns military base While the majority of soldiers withdrew from the Albu Aytha base prior to it being overrun Sunday by ISIS fighters, a number of soldiers appear to have been killed. Images posted online by ISIS purport to show the takeover of the base in question, and include images of men dressed in uniform who appear to be dead Iraqi soldiers. While CNN cannot independently verify the authenticity of the ISIS images, giveaway features on the base and in the landscape do appear to show western Iraq, specifically, and very likely the base in question. ISIS also seized a large weapons cache left behind at the base, al-Essawi said. Amid the continuing violence, a string of car bombs and mortar attacks hit Iraqi cities, leaving dozens dead. In Baghdad, two car bombs and seven mortar attacks struck primarily Shiite neighborhoods, killing at least nine people and wounding 40, police officials said. Car bombs also exploded in the predominantly Shiite cities of Hilla, Karbala and Basra, Iraqiya state TV reported. All three are south of the Iraqi capital. UK carries out first airstrikes The attacks came the same day that the United Kingdom said it conducted its first airstrikes against ISIS in Iraq, striking targets four days after Parliament voted to approve the country's involvement. British planes helped Kurdish troops who were fighting ISIS in northwestern Iraq, dropping a bomb on an ISIS heavy weapon position and shooting a missile at an armed pickup truck, the UK's defense ministry said. An initial assessment indicates both strikes were successful, according to the ministry. British planes had been involved in reconnaissance missions over Iraq in the days since lawmakers approved UK airstrikes against ISIS in Iraq on Friday, but Tuesday's strikes were a first. Britain joins the United States and France as countries that have hit ISIS in Iraq with airstrikes, while Belgium and Denmark have also said they also will provide planes. Of those nations, only the United States -- in partnership with some Arab countries -- have struck ISIS positions in neighboring Syria. Australia police arrest man accused of funding U.S. fighter in Syria Peshmerga 'need more support' In northern Iraq, Kurdish fighters known as Pershmerga, went after ISIS fighters in Rabia, a major border crossing between Syrian and Iraq that has been under the control of the militants since late June, Brig. Gen. Hazhar Ismail at the Peshmerga Ministry in Irbil told CNN. ISIS has been collecting money from people who use the border crossing, he said. The operation was preceded by coalition airstrikes. In Iraq, airstrikes overnight destroyed more ISIS transport and armored vehicles. There were also strikes near Mosul Dam, one of the country's largest hydroelectric dams, the U.S. military also said. The dam provides water to most of northern Iraq. There were also strikes northwest of Baghdad and one that hit west Fallujah, according to the military. On the ground, Hazhar said, the Kurdish forces needed closer air support in the form of helicopter cover during operations. He complained that the Peshmerga's budget, weapons and training must go through the central government in Baghdad and claimed that the Peshmerga &quot;have not received one dollar from Iraq, even though Parliament has approved funds.&quot; Opinion: To beat ISIS, focus on young people</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Europe's newest front line against ISIS: a Spanish town in North Africa</title>
        <author>Nima Elbagir Tim Lister</author>
        <corpus>Hanging around under overcast skies, a knot of men -- unshaven and dressed in a motley collection of T-shirts -- watch a convoy of Spanish military vehicles rumble by. They have reached this tiny Spanish enclave in North Africa overland -- from Mali, Syria, Libya and elsewhere. Some just want a better life in Europe; others are fleeing war. Some have clambered over the three 20-foot (6-meter) fences topped with razor-wire; others have bought forged Moroccan passports to take advantage of Moroccans' eligibility to enter Melilla as day-laborers or to trade. But the Spanish authorities fear that among this tide of the helpless may be some intent on bringing jihad to Europe, using the same routes used by people-smugglers across North Africa. The heavy police presence in Melilla -- the military helicopters, armored vehicles and patrol boats -- are part of their response. So are regular police raids on the poor, crowded neighborhood of Cañada, which sits on a hill overlooking the city center, with its elegant art-deco and modernist buildings, its elegant central park along the Avenida de la Democracia and sweep of sandy beaches. READ: ISIS fighter says airstrikes aren't effective 'Not welcome&quot; Foreigners, and especially journalists, are not welcome in Cañada, where at least one wall bears graffiti in support of the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria (ISIS) and others urge reclaiming everywhere from Sudan to Iraq as Islamist states. The imam of a mosque in Cañada is not available to talk. We are variously told he is sick or fasting, and are warned not to film in Cañada's precipitous alleys. The tension is greater than usual following a joint operation by Spanish and Moroccan security agencies last week. Eight men were arrested in the neighboring Moroccan town of Nador. The alleged ringleader of a cell said to have been recruiting would-be jihadists for Iraq and Syria was detained in Cañada. Mohamed Said Mohamed was arrested at his home, within a few hundred yards of the fence that separates Melilla from Morocco. The operation to arrest Mohammed was not without incident. A crowd gathered and threw stones at police in riot gear. At one point, witnesses said, police fired in the air as they tried to extricate Mohamed. Everything you need to know about ISIS Spanish police would also like to arrest his brother, Said Mohamed Zakarias, a former Spanish soldier trained in using explosives. After leaving the army in 2010, Zakarias headed south to Mali, where he joined the jihadist group MUJAO, an offshoot of al Qaeda in the Islamic Maghreb. In early 2012, MUJAO and other groups occupied nearly half of Mali, before French intervention drove them back into pockets of the Sahara. Spanish officials believe Zakarias moved onto Syria, and from there was in touch with his brother about recruiting young men from Morocco to join ISIS. The Moroccan government estimates some 2,000 Moroccans have gone to fight in Iraq and Syria, just as hundreds joined the insurgency in Iraq between 2005 and 2009. Mohamed was swiftly flown to Madrid to face a judge, Javier Bermudes. Denying him bail, Bermudes said Moroccan authorities determined that two men from the cell, had gone to an area of Syria and Iraq controlled by ISIS in July. Bermudes also expressed a fear widely held among Spanish officials, saying in his ruling that &quot;the threat posed by Spaniards or foreigners linked to Spain joining ISIS, or their hypothetical return to our country, is manifestly clear.&quot; This year, Spanish security forces have arrested 44 people - some in Melilla, some in Spain's other North African enclave of Ceuta, some on the mainland. According to the police, members of a Melilla group rounded up in May had dispatched 26 men — 24 Moroccans and two Spanish citizens — since 2012 to join Al Qaeda in the Islamic Maghreb and MUJAO. The migrants' center in Melilla is overcrowded, and according to some subsisting there, increasingly unhygienic. Designed to accommodate some 400 people, CETI holds more than 2,000. The Madrid government's representative in Melilla, Abdelmalik El Barkani. told CNN Tuesday that the conditions at the CETI were not ideal, but the care of migrants was adequate. &quot;Even though there are many more over the capacity, they have had all necessities covered, and they have been able to eat,&quot; he said. &quot;I believe that there they are much better than before they arrived in Melilla,&quot; El Barkani said. Other illegal migrants live on Melilla's streets. It seems a dead-end to many who have risked their lives to gain a toe-hold in Europe. 'Humiliated and abandoned' Some of the men loitering outside were from Kobani, the Kurdish town on the Syria-Turkey border now under an intense assault from ISIS. Thirty-four-year old Khalid Barazy has been in Melilla more than a month. &quot;The suffering that we've been living, it's impossible for another human to comprehend. For the last two days it's been raining and we've been sleeping under it,&quot; he said. &quot;We escaped death and now we're imprisoned here. Humiliated and abandoned. An entire people is being slaughtered. We escaped death and no one will grant us refuge.&quot; At once angry and despondent, Barazy added: &quot;My family are scattered between Turkey and Syria. Some are fighting ISIS, some have fled, some died.&quot; Barazy said that he and others from Kobani had first fled to Turkey but even there felt ISIS' presence. And so they had embarked on the long journey west. A few of the lucky ones had been able to fly to Algiers and travel overland into Morocco. Others had crossed one conflict zone after another, through Egypt, Libya and Algeria in a journey taking months. Another of the group, Mahmoud Bozan, said he had been smuggled across the border into Morocco and then into Melilla. He was clearly at his wits' end. &quot;It cost us catastrophic sums. Some people sold their houses, their furniture to get here. And look where we've ended up? I wish we'd stayed in Syria to kill and be killed. It would be better than the camp here.&quot; Their situation is full of ironies. As Barazy and others languish in Melilla, some from the Spanish territory and the Moroccan towns around it yearn to travel in the opposite direction, to join the war they have fled. They may use the same people-traffickers to help them do so. And according to Moroccan officials jihadist cells often share in those smuggling revenues. Barazy and the hundreds like him trapped in Melilla may gaze wistfully at the ferries leaving for the Spanish mainland while their asylum requests go unanswered or unresolved. What Spain fears is that others in Melilla, or planning to come here, see those ships as a passage to bring terror to Europe.</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>At least 9 killed when shells hit Ukrainian school and bus, officials say</title>
        <author>Victoria Butenko Jason Hanna</author>
        <corpus>Shells also hit a public transit bus in the city about the same time, killing six people in or near the vehicle, city officials said. The shelling in Donetsk, held for months by pro-Russian rebels, came despite a ceasefire that Ukraine's government reached with separatist leaders last month. A shell landed 5 meters from Donetsk's School 57 about 10 a.m., shattering windows and doors on the first and second floors, local officials said. It was the first day of the school year in rebel-controlled areas of the Donetsk region, a debut that was delayed by a month because of shelling and clashes between separatists and the Ukrainian military. Conflicting reports emerged over how many people were killed at the school. Officials at the rebel-held city office said a biology teacher and two parents died, and five other people were injured. Officials with the Donetsk regional authority, which is aligned with the Kiev government, said four people were killed and eight were injured. Both sides said no children died. It wasn't clear whether any of the injured were children. Though most Donetsk-area schools opened Wednesday, four of the region's 150 schools remained closed because of shelling, the rebels said on an official social media account. Nine Ukrainian soldiers killed in Donetsk fighting School 57 serves children ages 6 to 17, and more than 230 people were there at the time, including 70 children and 28 teachers, according to the website of the Kiev-aligned Donetsk regional authority. It wasn't immediately clear who was responsible for the shelling. The Donetsk regional authority blamed the rebels, who in turn blamed the Ukrainian military. Also Wednesday morning, a shell hit a small public transportation bus, killing six people -- two people inside and four who were nearby -- and injuring 25 others, the Donetsk city office said. It wasn't clear who fired that shell, either. Ukrainian government forces have been fighting pro-Russian separatists in eastern Ukraine for months. Both sides declared a ceasefire September 5, but some battles have taken place since then, including in Donetsk. Poroshenko: Reforms will set Ukraine on road to apply to join EU in 2020 On Monday alone, nine Ukrainian soldiers were killed in fighting at the city's airport, the government said. At least three civilians were killed in shelling in Donetsk from Sunday night into Monday morning, city officials said. Unrest in Ukraine began with protests in the country's capital last year after pro-Moscow President Viktor Yanukovych, favoring closer ties to Russia, dropped plans to sign a political and economic agreement with the European Union. After months of protests and days of deadly clashes between demonstrators and security personnel in Kiev, Parliament ousted Yanukovych in February. Weeks later, Russia annexed the Crimean Peninsula. In April, violence broke out in two Ukrainian regions that border Russia -- Donetsk and Luhansk -- as separatist leaders declared independence from the government in Kiev. Since mid-April, the conflict between the pro-Russian rebels and the Ukrainian military has cost more than 2,500 lives, according to the United Nations. Kiev and the West accuse Moscow of arming and supporting the rebels and of sending Russian troops over the border to fight them, a claim Moscow denies.</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Rafael Nadal makes winning return after three-month injury absence</title>
        <author></author>
        <corpus>On Tuesday, the Spaniard took to the court for the first time in three months and looked as though he had never been away as he blitzed past Frenchman Richard Gasquet at the China Open. Read: Nadal misses U.S. Open with wrist injury Needing just 78 minutes to win 6-4 6-0 in the opening round, the world No. 2 appeared to feel no effects of the right wrist injury he suffered while practicing at home in Mallorca in late July. &quot;In general, I have to be happy the way that I played,&quot; Nadal, a 14-time grand slam winner, told the official ATP Tour website. &quot;After three months without a match, winning against a good player like Richard is a very positive comeback for me. I think I played solid, no mistakes.&quot; Read: Chronic injuries force Li Na retirement Nadal, who presented Li Na with a bouquet of flowers as China said goodbye to its biggest tennis star on Tuesday, had not played since his surprise fourth round defeat by Australian Nick Kyrgios at Wimbledon on July 1. His problematic wrist meant he was unable to defend his title at this month's U.S. Open, where Croatia's Marin Cilic emerged as a surprise winner. &quot;More important than winning or losing is spending time on court. That's the key for me at the moment: spending time on court, playing matches,&quot; said Nadal. &quot;At least I am going to play two matches minimum here. That's a positive thing. I'm going to try my best to play three.&quot; Read: Nadal's uncle in sexism row The 28-year-old has returned to action even though he says his wrist is not quite 100% healed. Nadal has a decent record in Beijing -- having won the China Open in 2005 and Olympic gold in 2008. Last year, he finished runner-up as Novak Djokovic won his fourth China Open title. The Serb took his record in Beijing to 20-0 when beating Guillermo Garcia-Lopez 6-2 6-1 as Djokovic played his first match since being stunned by Japan's Kei Nishikori in the U.S. Open semifinal.</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Report: 40,000 migrant deaths worldwide since 2000</title>
        <author>Laura Smith-Spark</author>
        <corpus>More than half of those who died -- some 22,000 -- were trying to get to Europe, the IOM said. Nearly 6,000 more migrant deaths occurred along the U.S.-Mexico border and another 3,000 deaths from migration routes including Africa's Sahara Desert and the waters of the Indian Ocean, according to the group's research. &quot;Our message is blunt: migrants are dying who need not,&quot; said IOM Director General William Lacy Swing. &quot;It is time to do more than count the number of victims. It is time to engage the world to stop this violence against desperate migrants.&quot; The IOM report, published Monday and titled &quot;Fatal Journeys -- Tracking Lives Lost during Migration,&quot; puts the number of those killed trying to reach Europe at nearly 4,000 since the start of 2013. More than three-quarters of those victims died in the first nine months of this year, many of them drowning after being trafficked in unseaworthy vessels from the shores of the Middle East and North Africa across the Mediterranean. Two shipwrecks off the tiny Italian island of Lampedusa last October, in which more than 400 migrants died, made headlines around the world and prompted calls for action. Italy's navy launched Operation Mare Nostrum to try to find and rescue stranded migrants. Nonetheless, there have been many more shipwrecks and many more deaths in the year since. Just this month, witnesses told the IOM that as many as 500 people had died, including women and children, when human traffickers intentionally sunk their boat in the Mediterranean off Malta. Only 11 survivors have been found. Some of those on board were fleeing conflict in Syria or Gaza; others were looking for the chance to escape persecution or poverty and build a better life. Eritreans and Syrians made up the largest number of those arriving in Italy so far this year, the IOM said. Italian navy finds dozens of bodies in migrant boat Amnesty International: 'Survival test' Rights group Amnesty International released a new report Tuesday, accusing the European Union and its member states of &quot;imposing a survival test on refugees and migrants.&quot; Its research puts the number of those killed in the Mediterranean so far this year at at least 2,500 people. &quot;In the absence of safe and regular routes into Europe, accepting the risk of drowning in the central Mediterranean is the price many refugees and migrants must pay to access asylum or job opportunities,&quot; it said. The group calls for Europe to do more, pointing out that while Italy has shouldered the burden of migrant rescues in the Mediterranean over the past yea, it is unwilling to do so indefinitely. This is partly because it then takes responsibility for those rescued, who often want to reach other European nations. If Italy does scale down its operation without a new system in place or a better response by the European Union border agency, Frontex, many more lives will be lost at sea, the human rights group cautions. Amnesty International also warns that with the current unrest in the Middle East and long-running conflicts elsewhere, the number of people trying to reach Europe is unlikely to fall. Tens of thousands of people are trapped in increasingly lawless Libya, a major transit nation, and are seeking a way out, the report said. With the sealing off of land routes via Turkey, Greece and Bulgaria, many see no option but to embark on the dangerous journey by sea. &quot;In 2013, 48% of all irregular entrants and 63% of all those arriving irregularly by sea to the EU came from Syria, Eritrea, Afghanistan and Somalia, countries torn by conflict and widespread human rights abuses,&quot; the report said. 'Laughing' traffickers ram boat full of migrants and kill 500, survivors say 'Harsh response' to migrants The IOM warns that the true number of migrants killed is likely to be &quot;considerably higher&quot; than the number documented for its report. &quot;Although vast sums of money are spent collecting migration and border control data, very few agencies collect and publish data on migrant deaths,&quot; said IOM research chief Frank Laczko. Many migrants disappear and die without a trace as they make perilous journeys across deserts or seas. &quot;The paradox is that at a time when one in seven people around the world are migrants in one form or another, we are seeing an extraordinarily harsh response to migration in the developed world,&quot; said Swing. &quot;Limited opportunities for safe and regular migration drive would-be migrants into the hands of smugglers, feeding an unscrupulous trade that threatens the lives of desperate people. We need to put an end to this cycle. &quot;Undocumented migrants are not criminals. They are human beings in need of protection and assistance, and deserving respect.&quot; By highlighting the awful toll of migration, the IOM hopes to discourage would-be migrants from falling into the hands of unscrupulous criminal gangs and traffickers, as well as pressuring developed nations to change their policies to create more safe avenues of legal migration. U.S.-Mexico border An estimated 230 migrants died between January and September of this year trying to cross the U.S.-Mexico border, the report said. Because information from the region is so patchy, the figures don't include the likely several hundred people who die in Central America each year as they make their way north to the border. Between fiscal year 1998 and fiscal year 2013, a total of 6,029 migrants were found dead on the U.S. side of the border, the report said. About 100 lives a year have been lost on average in the seas bordering Australia, although the number has dropped off significantly this year, the IOM said. Most of those who travel by boat depart from Indonesia, with the vast majority in recent years coming from Afghanistan, Iraq, Iran and Sri Lanka.</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>9 Ukrainian soldiers killed in Donetsk fighting</title>
        <author>Victoria Butenko, Lindsay Isaac Jethro Mullen</author>
        <corpus>Twenty-seven were wounded in the fighting, said Andrey Lysenko, spokesman of the center, at his press briefing. In a separate incident, three civilians were killed and five injured in shelling overnight in Donetsk, the website of the city office said Monday. Residential and administrative buildings were damaged as a result of artillery fire, according to the site, which described the situation as tense. Ukrainian government forces have been fighting pro-Russian separatists in eastern Ukraine for months. Despite the ongoing violence in places such as Donetsk, Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko insisted last week that a ceasefire signed with rebel leaders more than three weeks ago was holding.</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>What Scotland's 'No' vote means for David Cameron</title>
        <author>Robin Oakley</author>
        <corpus>Cameron will also face an almighty battle in Parliament to deliver the consolation prize of greatly enhanced powers for the Scottish Parliament, the so-called &quot;Devo Max&quot; package, which he was forced to concede in the panicky latter stages of the No campaign. On Friday morning, the tired but relieved-looking Premier told reporters at 10 Downing Street that it would have broken his heart to see Scotland leave the UK. &quot;The people of Scotland have spoken,&quot; Cameron said. &quot;They have kept our country of four nations together, and like millions of other people, I am delighted.&quot; Cameron called on the country to move forward with a &quot;balanced settlement, fair to the people of Scotland -- and importantly, to everyone in England, Wales and Northern Ireland as well.&quot; But although Scottish voters ultimately rejected independence by a margin of 55% to 45%, this story is far from over for Cameron. READ: Scotland decides: The final count Did Gordon Brown save it? Cameron and his party were not the only ones to blame for a referendum campaign that so nearly led to the break-up of the United Kingdom. But he is being widely blamed for a variety of tactical and strategic errors. Many members of Parliament (MPs) will say that he and the &quot;Better Together&quot; campaign were only rescued by the campaigning fervor and passion of the former Labour Party leader and Prime Minister Gordon Brown. Cameron had sought to detach the questions of Scottish independence and his own future. Warning the Scots that what they were walking into was not a trial separation but a final break, he pleaded with them not to throw away the union in a protest vote just because they disliked him and his party. (Of the 59 Scottish seats in the Westminster Parliament only one is held by a Conservative MP). QUIZ: How Scottish are you? Insisting on the finality of a constitutional divorce was probably his best card. But in emphasizing that the question on the ballot paper was not his future but the future of the union, Cameron was also acknowledging that he is held to blame by many for boosting the nationalist vote. Where Cameron went wrong He is blamed firstly for the terms he agreed on the staging of the referendum. Critics lambast Cameron now for giving Scottish National Party leader Alex Salmond two years to build momentum for his cause, and for opening the vote to 16 year olds. They blame him for agreeing to a ballot paper question which meant that the supporters of independence were the ones campaigning for a &quot;Yes&quot; while their opponents were bound to look negative in seeking a &quot;No.&quot; They blame him for agreeing to let one vote decide the issue: when a Labour government in the 1970s agreed to a referendum on setting up a Scottish Parliament it insisted that 40% of those voting must approve the change. There was a majority for the Parliament but the 40% margin was not achieved and the Scots had to wait another 20 years for their own Parliament. Above all, the critics insist Cameron was wrong to exclude from the ballot paper the compromise option of the so-called &quot;Devo Max&quot; — a huge extension in the tax-raising and spending powers of the Scottish Parliament. This devolution of power from London to Edinburgh appealed to many as an achievable compromise which would have taken the steam out of the separatist case. But Cameron overruled such advice, only to find that he and the other Westminster party leaders were forced to concede Devo Max anyway — win or lose the vote — as the campaign threatened to run away from them. Even during the lead-up to the vote, when many Conservative MPs kept quiet for fear of making things worse for the Better Together campaign, some were warning that the concessions on Devo Max wrung from Cameron by Gordon Brown might not be deliverable. What comes next? Conservative MPs are already vociferously demanding that any concessions to the Scottish Parliament must be balanced by greater powers for the English regions -- namely, by reducing the number of Scottish MPs in the Westminster Parliament and by ending the process whereby Scottish MPs at Westminster can vote on English-only matters while English MPs have no say in matters delegated to the Scottish Parliament. As a moderate and pragmatic politician, Cameron has had an uneasy tenure already over a right-leaning party growing ever more Euro-skeptic as it faces the rise of the United Kingdom Independence Party (UKIP). The further difficulties he will face in pushing through legislation to honor his commitments to the Scots will do nothing to add to his authority. But Cameron will breathe a sigh of relief at a partial reprieve: had he seen the Scots depart from the UK he might well have faced a rebellion in his party which could have gone as far as the tabling of a vote of no confidence in his leadership -- a process which requires 15% of his MPs (46 of them) to sign up to the proposition. For the moment at least he soldiers on. But there is further trouble looming. Opinion polls indicate that next month his party will lose its first Parliament seat to UKIP in a by-election caused by the defection of former Tory MP Douglas Carswell. READ: 5 inspired secessionist movements</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Time to give Ukraine defensive weapons</title>
        <author>Steven Pifer Strobe Talbott</author>
        <corpus>Russia illegally occupied and annexed Crimea in March. Just weeks later, armed separatists -- assisted and, in some cases, led by Russian intelligence officers -- began seizing government buildings in the eastern Ukrainian regions of Donetsk and Luhansk. Ukrainian counterattacks started making headway in the summer. Russia responded by supplying heavy weapons to the separatists -- including, it is widely believed, the Buk anti-aircraft system believed to have shot down Malaysia Airlines flight 17 in mid-July. Despite the influx of arms, Ukrainian forces continued to make progress. By early August, the separatists looked on the verge of defeat. That would have stopped Putin's strategy in its tracks. So, as NATO noted, elite Russian military units invaded and occupied Ukrainian territory, hitting Ukrainian forces hard. Vastly outgunned, Poroshenko had little choice but to accept a ceasefire on September 5. The truce is shaky, but the Ukrainian president seems intent on pursuing a peaceful settlement. Whether common ground can be found among Kiev, the separatists and Moscow is unclear. At best, the negotiation will be long and arduous. The Ukrainian government has for some time sought lethal military assistance, such as anti-armor weapons, as well as secure communications equipment and reconnaissance drones. When he hosts Poroshenko in the Oval Office, Obama should agree to provide defensive arms on an expedited basis. Such assistance would enhance Kiev's ability to deter further Russian aggression, aggression that would threaten, perhaps fatally, the possibility of a negotiated settlement. A better-armed Ukrainian military would give Putin pause, because it could impose greater costs on the Russian army if the Russians break the ceasefire and renew the fighting. Reports detail the extraordinary lengths, such as nighttime burials, to which the Kremlin has gone to hide from its public the fact that Russian soldiers have fought and died in Ukraine. The more costly the Ukrainians can make any fighting for the Russians, the less Moscow's interest in resuming the conflict. Some may argue that providing lethal military assistance would provoke Putin to escalate. But he has already escalated the situation -- from instigating separatist actions to providing heavy weapons to sending in the Russian army. This suggests the opposite may well prove true: Arming Ukraine will raise the costs of escalation to Russia and thus make it less likely. Putin has made clear his contempt for the Western response to date. Inaction could embolden him to escalate in Ukraine and test the waters elsewhere, perhaps in a NATO member state such as Estonia. Moreover, the Ukrainians will bear the risks and brunt of any escalation. If they are willing to accept those risks, we should give them the tools to defend themselves. And there is an additional important reason to respond favorably to Ukraine's request for defensive arms: to restore credibility to the notion of security assurances. In December 1994, the leaders of the United States, Britain and Russia signed the Budapest memorandum on security assurances, which committed those countries to respect Ukraine's sovereignty and territorial integrity and not use force against Ukraine. Those commitments paved the way for Kiev's decision to give up about 1,900 strategic nuclear warheads, at the time the world's third-largest nuclear arsenal. Moscow has grossly violated the Budapest memorandum by its seizure of Crimea and assaults on Ukraine. The United States and Britain have an obligation to respond. Washington has imposed economic sanctions on Russia and provided Ukraine a modest amount of nonlethal military aid. Those are appropriate steps, but they do not suffice. Last Friday, former President Leonid Kuchma, who signed the Budapest memorandum for Ukraine, suggested his country had been cheated. That reflects general sentiment in Kiev. The widely held impression that Moscow has violated its Budapest commitments at low cost badly weakens the value of security assurances in the future. That is unfortunate, as security assurances could play a role as part of the package to resolve the Iran and North Korea nuclear issues. But how much value will security assurances have if Tehran and Pyongyang see that they can be violated with relative impunity? Washington can change that impression. Providing lethal military assistance to Ukraine could not only deter Putin from further war against Ukraine, but could help to reestablish security assurances as part of the solution to critical nuclear proliferation challenges.</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Barack Obama has a plan to take out ISIS -- but who's with him?</title>
        <author>Nick Thompson, </author>
        <corpus>U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry is sweeping through the Middle East to try to convince regional leaders to back America's plan to beat back the terror group, which has seized a large chunk of territory stretching from northern Syria to central Iraq with alarming pace in recent months. So who's with them? .</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Opinion: For all NATO's words, Ukraine still faces Russia alone</title>
        <author>Marcin Zaborowski,</author>
        <corpus>However, as often happens, the summit agenda was hijacked by more current and dramatic developments: the rise of ISIS in Iraq and Russia's push into Ukraine. Both these developments have reminded NATO that its core business -- the defense of its member states -- needs to be returned to the center of the alliance's agenda. Russia's annexation of Crimea and continued push into the south-east of Ukraine -- a NATO partner country -- has inevitably provoked fear amongst Ukraine's neighbors, all of whom have relatively fresh memories of Russian domination. These countries -- Poland and the Baltic states in particular -- made sure that the Ukrainian crisis would be at the center of the Newport agenda. This happened in two ways. The Central East European allies asked for measures that would reassure them by confirming NATO's engagement in the face of Russian aggression. In addition, the show of solidarity with Ukraine became a major focus of the summit, which was attended by Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko. The outcome of the Newport summit has met these allies' expectations, at best, halfway. The biggest change came in the rhetoric and positioning of the alliance's key members. Until very recently, NATO has prioritized its partnership with Russia, taking great care not to offend it. When in 1997 the Alliance started the process of taking in new members from Central and Eastern Europe, it mollified Moscow by setting up a separate Russia Council and signing a partnership agreement that excluded the presence of a major Western force in new member states. Russia's actions in Ukraine have made the pretense of partnership ridiculous and as much was acknowledged by NATO states in Newport. On his way to the summit, U.S. President Barack Obama paid a visit to Estonia where he delivered a Reaganesque speech pledging full solidarity with the Baltic states. Meantime German Chancellor Angela Merkel condemned Russian aggression in Ukraine and reasserted the viability of NATO's collective defense measures. Overall, the rhetoric of partnership with Russia -- which has dominated past meetings -- disappeared in Newport where it was replaced by the rhetoric of facing-up to an adversarial Russia. However, whilst NATO leaders were strong in words, the decisions they took in response to the Russian threat were at best modest. At the height of crisis during the Cold War the U.S. presence in Western Europe reached more than 277,000 troops. By comparison the U.S. said earlier this month that it had 57,000 active service members in Europe. Of these only a very small number are based in Poland and the Baltic States. Decisions taken in Newport have not changing these facts in a meaningful way. Whilst NATO announced a creation of a spearhead force, consisting of a Rapid Reaction Force, frequent exercises and logistical centers, this initiative will not change the strategic balance in Central and Eastern Europe. The units contributing to the rapid-reaction force will remain within the states that designate them, meaning their availability will be subject to political approval. The exercises that would bring together U.S. and European troops are meant to be frequent or even &quot;persistent&quot; but their scope will remain small. The logistical centers that are meant to be based in Poland and the Baltic states are perhaps the most concrete of the approved measures. If developed they would commence integrating Central and Eastern Europe into the NATO infrastructure. Overall, the reassurance measures for Central and Eastern Europe are not game-changers, but they are going in the right direction and could suggest a beginning of rebalancing of the current vastly unequal situation in the region. However, as far as Ukraine itself is concerned the summit offered Kiev close to nothing. The announcement that NATO would spend 15 million euros ($19M) on military aid to Ukraine did not impress the Ukrainians nor the Russians. NATO's decision to allow individual members of the alliance to sell arms to Ukraine has not changed anything, not least because since then a number of states have rushed to deny they intended to sell anything to Ukraine whilst the unstable situation there continues. In other words, after the summit Ukraine continues to be on its own vis-a-vis belligerent Russia. NATO's failure to send a clear signal to Russia by supporting Ukraine represents in itself a grave threat to the alliance's Central East European members -- who may be next on the list of potential Russian targets.</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Supermodel Liu Wen: How I survive fashion week</title>
        <author>Allyssia Alleyne</author>
        <corpus>Liu is one of the world's highest-paid models and the first Chinese face to crack the top five in Forbes' annual list of top earners. She says that far from being a week long party, Paris Fashion Week is an arduous mix of shoots, shows and limited sleep. Models, even well-known ones like Liu, turn up at fashion week with no shows booked and are often slotted in just 24 hours before the shows are scheduled to start. In the meantime, they just have to sit it out and wait for a designer to call, although when you are as big as Wen, you know the phone will ring. Next come fittings, and although models like Liu look exquisite in whatever they wear, not every collection will suit her body shape or complexion. &quot;(A designer might) design a big coat,&quot; explains Liu. &quot;So ... the model (must have) big shoulders to hang the clothes.&quot; That means, that even after a fitting, Lui still won't know if she'll walk the show. The 26-year-old admits it can be a whirl: &quot;When I am in Paris, I have no idea what my schedule (is) ... everything is always last minute. You don't know exactly what you are doing. You only know you have to wake up, the driver take you, you go in the back seat, you have make-up, hair, and then walk in the show and then the driver take you and you go and walk in another show. &quot;Sometimes you know, we have a crazy schedule. One time, I did 27 shows in London, and 22 or 23 shows in Paris. I don't know how I did it!&quot; Looking fresh in the midst of a tough schedule requires insider knowledge. Here Liu shares with CNN the survival secrets that get her through fashion week. Always be prepared &quot;During Fashion Week, you always know about your schedule at the last minute,&quot;says Liu, who walked a record 74 shows during the Fall/Winter 2009 season. This means models must always be ready to dash out to a fitting, casting or catwalk at the drop of a hat. Get plenty of beauty sleep -- when you can Between early call-times and late-night runway shows, Wen can be up and about from 5am to midnight. But it's still important for her to squeeze in as much sleep as possible. &quot;I think (sleep) is really good for skin,&quot; she says. &quot;When you sleep very well and eat healthy, you look well and very beautiful.&quot; Stay hydrated &quot;For Fashion Week, the girls are always running around backstage from a show to another show,&quot; Liu says. &quot;I always have one bottle of water because sometimes you are very thirsty.&quot; It's also not rare for stylists to use bottled water to rinse wash a model's hair when there are no sinks available. Find your relaxation technique and stick to it For Wen, this means bringing her own music to listen to backstage, as well as a good book. And to unwind physically? &quot;I bring a very cute massage ball. Sometimes in the evening I do a little bit massage to make my body more relaxed.&quot; Show off your personal style Wen may have made her fortune showing off others' designs, but she feels that showing off her own style is also important. &quot;I think the personal style for model is very important because I think it can show that all the girls have very different personalities,&quot; Liu says. &quot;When you have your own style you just represent yourself.&quot; Make time for your friends &quot;Most of the time we live in different countries or different cities,&quot; Liu says. &quot;We don't have that much time to hang out, and only (during) fashion week we can see each other a lot backstage. That's why I love to take a picture, and then sometimes just have fun!&quot; Don't forget your map (or at least Google Maps) &quot;After six years doing shows I still don't know Paris very well!&quot; Enjoy yourself In spite of the stress of the shows, Wen is appreciative of the chance to be working in the City of Lights at all. &quot;I do love Paris Fashion Week because Paris is a very beautiful city,&quot; she says. &quot;When I was young, I dreamed (of coming) to Paris.&quot; The pampered life of Karl Lagerfeld's pet cat Front-row politics, no-show models: What really goes on backstage at a fashion show Paris Fashion Week -- in photos</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>The fashion prodigy behind Kim, Kendall and Rihanna's megawatt glamor</title>
        <author></author>
        <corpus>Instead, the 28-year-old is at the helm of one of the most venerable fashion houses in the world -- Balmain. Since taking over in 2011, the Bordeaux-born prodigy has been credited with bringing a fresh, popular-culture aesthetic to the house, while staying true to its spirit and tradition. His richly embroidered, luxurious designs have earned him legions of fans, and his so-called &quot;Balmain Army&quot; of supporters includes some of the most glamorous women in the world, from Naomi Campbell to Rosie Huntington-Whitely. Rousteing, who at 25 was the youngest creative director of a Parisian label since the legendary Yves Saint Laurent took the top job at Christian Dior in the 1950s, has also been hailed as a champion of diversity, casting mixed-race and Asian models in his catwalk shows and advertising campaigns. The designer tells CNN about his love of &quot;wonder women,&quot; the meaning of luxury, and his friendship with his muse, Rihanna. CNN: What is at the heart of the Balmain DNA? Olivier Rousteing: Pierre Balmain has always been a big designer like Christian Dior or Monsieur Saint Laurent, and when I had this opportunity to take (on) the house I just felt so flattered ... it was an honor for me. And at the same time I wanted to bring back the archives because Pierre Balmain was known for the Jolie Madame silhouette, amazing tailoring and the most incredible embroideries, but I wanted to twist it with my edge, my generation. And I was excited to express all these feelings -- all my culture I had today with all the past of the house which is so huge and so interesting and impressive. CNN: How does your style differ from former creative director Christophe Decarnin? OR: I learned a lot from Christophe. And when I was working at Balmain as an assistant and managing the studio, my job was translating everything he wanted in a fashion way. But Christophe was from another age, another generation, loving different muses and icons. He was more into Kate Moss, rock and roll and Sex Pistols, the 1980s. What I loved about him was all the sex appeal that he wanted to introduce to the house. But my generation is all hip hop, a different culture. Even top models that inspire me didn't inspire him -- it is just a matter of generation. And I think what is important for me today is underlining the luxury of the house, maybe less jeans, less street wear, but keeping the DNA of Pierre Balmain and pushing the embroideries and the craftsmanship because this is something that I think is part of me, and part of the house at the same time. CNN: What is it about Rihanna that inspired you? OR: Rihanna has been my muse from the beginning. I have been listening to her albums since I was young and followed her career. I love women and I love wonder women -- those kind of women who have no boundaries and no (limits) and have this power to express themselves. And I had the chance to meet her two years ago and it was love at first sight -- literally. She showed me how to believe in myself and push the boundaries and limits at the same time keeping control of your life and that I think is the best I could learn from her. CNN: Did you feel pressure for your first show for Balmain in 2011? OR: Actually, I think the first show is the easiest one because you don't know what you expect. But the first minute that I went out on the runway I just realized that my life is going to change. From the second show you realize what it means to be a creative director -- you are more exposed and people don't see you just as a designer -- your personality is really important and they sometimes don't judge you only on your clothes. CNN: What has been the greatest advantage -- and hindrance -- of your youth in this industry?  OR: For me it is really important not to lose faith. When you are a baby you just dream to be the President -- you dream to be Miss Universe or whatever -- you don't have boundaries. And I think youth helps (me) to just believe and think there are no boundaries and no (limits). If I had this job at 45 or 40, I don't think I would do the same clothes, I don't think I would express myself in the same way and thanks to my youth I believe so much and I push my boundaries so strongly . CNN: Is it hard to stay grounded? OR: No, because I am close to people who are true and down to earth, and so for me it's not like, 'Oh I am only with celebrities or the woman who is 60 and wearing my clothes.' I have met so many celebrities who are arrogant and hardcore -- they are not my friends. I am just a simple person and maybe it seems weird to say that but sometimes the greatest luxury is to remain true to yourself. CNN: Tell us about your love of Instagram. OR: What is important in my career and my way of being a designer is Instagram. Obviously people see I am selling a dress at $25,000 and that I have this life with celebrities, taking flights all the time ... but with my Instagram people can realize who I am. I can wake up and do a selfie in my flat, go to the gym like 75% of the population, you know, just be normal! CNN: Talk about the inspiration behind this collection. OR: When Rihanna came to my after party last winter she was dressed in my leather skirt a beautiful see-through top, and she was kind of naked underneath. That inspired the whole collection. But it is a happy, joyful collection showing the state of my mind today. I am enjoying my work, I am celebrating my youth, my generation. There is a lot of work behind it, still keeping the couture element, still keeping this dreamy thing that I always have. CNN: What are the last minute preparations in the atelier ahead of the show like? OR: I'm really a control freak! At Balmain, everything needs to come five days before -- that is my limit. But it is still very last minute but really exciting because obviously we get some (pieces) that are really well done, but with others you are like, 'Oh my God, I need to redo it!' I have an amazing team that believes in me and the brand. CNN: What, for you, is the sign of success? OR: When people who I am close to tell me that something is good. You know, in fashion you can't trust too many people. But the people who you trust, you can be sure of, and they are going to tell you the truth, when it's bad and when it's good and that's what I want. But the most important thing is to please myself. If you are sure of yourself, if you like your show people are also going to love it. Read: Front-row politics, no-show models: What really goes on backstage at a fashion show Look: Paris Fashion Week in photos</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Private jets, two maids and a personal chef: The pampered life of Karl Lagerfeld's pet cat</title>
        <author></author>
        <corpus></corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Stealing from nature: Incredible new tech inspired by biology</title>
        <author>Kieron Monks</author>
        <corpus>It is a reliable and effective response, and what is good enough to protect our health has also proved capable of safeguarding inboxes. Artificial immune systems (AIS) based on the body's cellular response to disease are being used to target spam. 'It's an adaptive system that can be more nuanced in detecting what's dangerous&quot;, says Dr. Uwe Aickelin, professor of computer science at the university of Nottingham and leading AIS developer. &quot;Millions of pieces of information are gathered so the cells are very accurate.&quot; While the cells in our bodies will respond to signals such as stress and inflammation, Aickelin's software analogue picks up on the traffic bombardments associated with spam. While generic filters can cope with conventional phishing, the cellular system is suited to a user facing frequent new threats, and has been employed by leading security companies. This model represents a potentially transformative shift in the rapidly expanding field of biomimicry. The trend for nature-inspired designs has spread across industries from crab-style deep-sea vessels to insect-inspired buildings, and is projected to generate $1.6 trillion by 2030 according to Da Vinci Index. But now technologies based specifically on cellular designs are making nature itself the driving force. In addition to computing, cellular biomimicry is making its mark in water filtration, meeting President Nixon's historic challenge to make the oceans drinkable, using a membrane present in humans and plants. Meanwhile, photosynthetic processes are being applied to the capture and storage of solar energy, while millions of dollars have been invested in applying the properties of lung cells to building exteriors -- the 'Eskin' - to create a layer that allows them to interact efficiently with both people and the environment. &quot;It represents a shift and ultimately where we are heading&quot;, Janine Benyus, biologist, author and founder of Biomimcry 3.8 told CNN. &quot;We have become very successful in mimicking form, but the real transformational change comes in how we build our material world. Every day we are learning more about molecular machinery in cells and how they work so as to understand and use their design principles is key. These principles are being applied to some of the most critical resource issues, including fuel through the development of biobatteries. Researchers at the University of Utah have created a battery based on the process of metabolism, using sugar as fuel, catalyzed with the natural energy conversion properties of enzymes. &quot;If you see a small child consume sugar they convert it to run around all day, so it's very efficient and we take the same pathways to apply to the battery&quot;, says lead developer Shelley Minteer, who claims the design has favorable performance qualities. The biobattery can already operate devices such as smartphones, and may prove more versatile than traditional batteries as it can function in extremely low temperatures. The technology is proved to the extent that offshoot company Akermin has received a $3 million grant to use the technology in one of the US' largest carbon cleaning operations in power plants. The combination of living process and synthetic materials is rarely seamless, Minteer admits. Yet advances in the technology of modeling are now allowing greater control and accuracy. Scientists can sculpt the synthesized cells at nano scale into ever more efficient arrangements, getting closer to the natural design. Visualization tools are being driven by creative fields, notably architecture, while manufacturing is improving rapidly through 3D printing. There are skeptics that believe natural processes are being too readily applied. &quot;Natural systems evolved for very specific reasons, over millions of years, with very specific parameters, scale-lengths, forces, and the process of translating these phenomena to other scales, function and human desires does not come naturally or directly.&quot;, Skylar Tibbits, lead researcher at MIT's self-assembly lab, argued in a 2013 TED talk. &quot;We should not simply assume that systems working at nanoscales can easily be translated to large scales.&quot; Critics have also warned of 'Jurassic Park' unpredictable and unwanted side effects when natural process are transplanted into technology. Such effects have been noted in Uwe Ackelein's anti-spam program, where the target adapts the defense as well as vice versa. But these risks pale compared to the potential benefits, exponents believe. Using the processes of nature can deliver designs uniquely adaptive to the environment, with better function and resource management, that can transform industries to deliver solutions to the most critical questions of the age. Read more from Make, Create, Innovate: Forget wearable tech, embeddable implants are already here This 'Star Trek'-style molecular sensor fits in your hand, reads your food 'Miracle material' graphene one step closer to commercial use</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Would you live in a house made of sand and bacteria? It's a surprisingly good idea</title>
        <author>Kieron Monks ,</author>
        <corpus>A lab technician introduced Trimble to Sporosarcina pasteurii, a bacterium with binding qualities, sometimes used to solidify soil to hold road signs in place. The student tested it with one of the world's most abundant resources - sand. Pumping bacterial solution into a sand-filled mould, he added nutrients, urea derived from urine as fertilizer and calcium. After a year, and hundreds of failed experiments, this process manufactured a stool around 70% the compression strength of concrete. The process requires less than one-sixth of the energy used in concrete production, and is completely biodegradable. Crucially, Trimble believes his mechanism has the added benefit that it could be employed by anyone, anywhere. &quot;Once you have the basic framework it should be transferable. Imagine a Tsunami-hit farm in Indonesia that is not getting supplies. You could use sand and bacteria on site, practically free, and have shelter housing that is far more permanent.&quot; Trimble is working with NGOs to apply Dupe to Aboriginal settlements and insecure regions of Morocco. But while the applications are new and experimental, the concept of growing the material for our built environment is increasingly regarded as not merely interesting, but essential. According to the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, the construction industry accounts for 40% of the world's C02 emissions, 40% of U.S. landfill and has been uniquely resistant to change. Concrete, bricks and cement have remained the dominant materials since the industrial revolution in the early 19th century, and as pressure mounts on resources and climate, scientists and architects are looking to the natural world for solutions. Building bacteria Bacteria have been at the center of alternative methods. North Carolina start-up Biomason is growing bricks on an industrial scale, cultivated from sand by microorganisms. The company has won major prizes and funding for the bricks, which will be used in a structure for the first time this year in a pedestrian walkway, ahead of building projects across the world. Similar processes are being developed to build in the most challenging environments. British architects see an opportunity to cultivate new life in deserts, while NASA believe bacteria could allow the construction of bases on other planets without the headache of ferrying the material there. While bacterial processes save heavily on carbon, there are concerns that by-products could be poisonous. But another living brick -- made from mushrooms -- has no such problems. Functional fungus New York firm Ecovative are producing materials that combine agricultural waste products such as corn stock with mushroom mycelium -- the roots of the vegetable. Over five days the mycelium binds the waste to create a block with a stronger compressive strength than concrete, with none of the heat or energy required by regular bricks. The product is in commercial use for packaging, producing thousands of units a month, and the company is expanding into construction. Ecovative believe that in addition to being renewable and decomposable, natural properties give them a performance advantage. &quot;It has great insulation properties&quot;, says Sam Harrington, Ecovative Director of Sustainability. &quot;A key benefit is flame resistance -- without adding any chemicals we were able to achieve a Class A fire rating&quot;. There is scope for development. Mycelium effectively dies once its growth is complete, but Harrington is looking ahead to material that does not. &quot;We are exploring ideas of living materials, perhaps that are self-healing or respond to leaks with indicators.&quot; Ecovative are in dialogue with major construction companies, and the material will soon be tested on a historic scale. A collaboration with architects The Living won the prestigious MOMA (Museum of Modern Art) PS-1 competition, and their creation will be installed in the museum courtyard this summer. Growing for gold &quot;Hy-Fi&quot; will be the largest ever grown structure, and first large building to claim zero carbon emissions. It will be formed of three 40-foot spiral towers constructed from the mushroom material, with varying properties of brick to maximise light and ventilation. The material's versatility offers unique design opportunities, says David Benjamin, lead architect of the project. &quot;You can dial in almost any performance you want. You can mix and match a variety of properties such as water resistance or UV resistance, lightness or durability. You can grow the bricks in almost any shape&quot; Benjamin says the bio-bricks could be made to last as long as traditional materials, but believes architecture must embrace temporary structures. &quot;It's essential to recognize that not all materials should last for centuries. A lot of the steel in our buildings will last longer than we need. Our idea is a building that be made locally and quickly, and then have a plan for when the life of the building is over.&quot; Future applications would include pop-up stores, festival &quot;tents&quot; and emergency shelters, says Benjamin, but there are greater hopes for the material within the industry. Stronger than concrete &quot;I could imagine every structure you would built out of bricks&quot;, says Dirk Hebel, Assistant Professor of Architecture and Construction at the Future Cities Laboratory in Singapore. &quot;No high-rises, but smaller scale structures and houses. The material is stronger than concrete, with better insulation capacities&quot;. The challenge will come in commercializing the products, Hebel feels. &quot;There is huge demand for alternative materials. The question is how easy it is to penetrate the existing market. This needs time and a couple of buildings to show the possibilities&quot;. Stealing from nature Another, more radical approach takes the material from nature but also allows it to build the structure. Michael Pawlyn, director of Exploration Architecture, is a leading figure in biomimicry, having previously applied natural processes to create man-made forests in England and the Sahara Desert. His latest project to grow a &quot;small venue for spoken word performances&quot; from undersea biorock was recently unveiled at the Architecture Foundation in London. &quot;In biology, complex structures achieve resource efficiency by putting things in exactly the right place, which is very difficult with made materials&quot;, says Pawlyn. &quot;Our ways should deliver significant resource savings.&quot; Drawing on the natural accumulation of coral reefs, his team would install a steel frame in the deep ocean and leave it to attract material. Growth would be focused on specific areas of need using an electrical current. &quot;We're interested in looking at its structural growth patterns. We have stress gauges on the structure to measure force in particular areas. If one is highly stressed, we can input more current so the rate of deposition matches the force.&quot; Pawlyn believes the structure could be built within two years, for consideration at scale. As with Ecovative, a key challenge ahead is to integrate still-living material to allow intelligent biosensors that respond to the building occupants. Innovators in this space acknowledge the ongoing barriers presented in an industry that has resisted modernization. But from rock to fungus, sand to space dust, the use of materials and processes designed by nature herself offer both a solution to the sustainability crisis, and a glimpse of our new built environment: clean, efficient, and alive. Read more from Make, Create, Innovate: Music 'hackers' unleash new generation of cool and bizarre instruments Forget wearable tech, embeddable implants are already here Feeling glum, happy, aroused? New technology can detect your mood</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Gone in 12 seconds: NASCAR crew's super-fast pit stops</title>
        <author>Earl Nurse</author>
        <corpus>Greg Morin is head coach of the 48 pit crew at Hendrick Motorsports, the team that helped one of NASCAR's most successful drivers, Jimmie Johnson, win six championships. &quot;It is safe to say that if you don't have a well performing pit crew that executes well on pit road, you are going to affect the overall outcome of the race in a potentially hugely negative manner,&quot; says Morin. He adds: &quot;Our goal is to hit a 12-second pit stop, hit five lug nuts off, five lug nuts on (on each wheel) ... get it full of fuel and ship it down pit road.&quot; Watch the video above to see the Hendrick Motor Sports' 48 pit crew in action.</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>The submarine that found a lost H-bomb: 'Alvin' reveals the mysteries of the deep</title>
        <author>Lauren Said-Moorhouse</author>
        <corpus>In the darkness, a serene atmosphere surrounds the two scientists and pilot who occasionally snap out of their thoughts to gaze at electric sparks of fluorescence emanating from animals bioluminescing as the sub passes by. The radio crackles as the pilot navigates to the dive site with guidance from the systems on the research vessel Atlantis, floating above. As they begin their final approach to the seafloor, activity erupts in the sub as powerful quartz iodide and metal halide lights break the intense blackness and weights are dropped to slow the sub. The team take in their surroundings and maneuver the vehicle towards the dive site, and the day's work aboard the historic submersible &quot;Alvin&quot; can finally begin. Pioneering ocean research Run by the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute, the U.S. Navy-owned manned vehicle has been traversing the world's oceans for half a century, revealing mysteries of the deep with every expedition. &quot;I would suspect that on every dive we've ever been on, we've probably run across something no one's ever seen,&quot; says Alvin expedition leader Bruce Strickrott. &quot;Not only is [Alvin] valuable, it's a heck of an experience. There isn't a person who dives in the submarine who won't remember it for the rest of the lives.&quot; He adds that Alvin played a crucial part in demonstrating that hydrothermal vents in the ocean are capable of sustaining living organisms. &quot;From a scientific standpoint, Alvin was instrumental in bringing people to the hydrothermal sites and finding life, particularly down by the Galapagos in the '70s,&quot; he says. &quot;From the late '60s and on into the '70s, Alvin was starting to ramp up as a tool and when they took people down to the vents and they were able to see life down there, I think that's when its value really took off.&quot; Hunt for a missing H-bomb Today, it is equipped with state-of-the-art tech including robotic arms and still and video cameras, and several reconstructions over the decades mean the sub can safely bring scientists down 4,500 meters below the surface. Read: Swimming with sharks, without a cage During the sub's lifetime, it has undertaken some fascinating adventures including the search for a missing hydrogen bomb off the coast of Spain in 1966, after an Air Force B-52 and a tanker plane collided over Spain during air-to-air refueling, dropping an unexploded H-bomb into the Mediterranean sea. Alvin spent three months searching for the bomb on the sea floor before locating it and enabling it to be recovered by a remote controlled submersible. Alvin also made an exploratory survey of RMS Titanic in 1986 and investigated the aftermath of the 2010 Deepwater Horizon oil spill and associated environmental implications. It may be half a century old, but Strickrott believes it could go on exploring the oceans for another 50 years. &quot;Next year it will head around South America, coming up to Barbados and head out to the Mid-Atlantic.&quot; He adds: &quot;If you look at all the dives ever, you've barely scratched the possibilities. There is an awful lot out there that we just don't know. Science is what drives us, but we have to have the desire to go there.&quot; Click through the gallery above to explore some of Alvin's many achievements. Read: Swimming with sharks, without a cage Read: Does 'immortal' jellyfish have the secret to everlasting life? WATCH: Photographer captures bioluminescence</corpus>
        <section>EUROPE</section>
    </article>
</news_list>
